--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制:呆呆熊  双语合成:悠悠  翻译校正:cc  招募Q号:76846146
呃 你死了吗？
你 你是在浪费
那又怎么样？
我比你受欢迎
打开通往蓝精灵村庄的大门
- 哦 亲爱的现在 您来晚了 - 谢谢 谢谢
- 给您一张节目单好吗 拿着吧 - 是的 是的
有请最伟大的魔法师 格格巫先生出场
演员通道
对不起 先生 您不能进来 这是规定
- 您懂英语吗？- 我听不懂你在说什么
真不好意思
- 你好 女士 - 你好
不行 需要您的房卡
对 我明白 非常感谢
员工衣帽间
请让一下
菜好了 快给客人端过去 快点
- 嘿 你 把这个菜 端到5号桌 - 好的 好的
格格巫先生 拿破仑套房
你看那边 你看那边
- 罗浮宫 好无趣啊 我们去玩摩天轮吧 - 我想去啊
再见 傻瓜
纪念乔纳森·温特斯
感谢乔纳森赋予蓝爸爸生命
让蓝精灵在这个世界上有一席之地
Time to smurf some magic.
Let's see.
There you are.
Mimosa pollen.
Yes, tiger lily
to make her essence magical and blue.
Unless this spell be all for naught,
the final thing, one hopeful thought.
Once upon a time, in Smurf Village,
happy Smurfs were going about their happy lives
completely unaware that not too far away,
the evil wizard Gargamel
was concocting a diabolical plan.
Hey.
Hey!
Smooth, you're upstaging the narrator.
Yo, take it down a notch, my blues brothers.
- All right. All right. - Thank you. Anyway...
So Gargamel said,
"I am making my own irresistible creation,
"the Smurfette, to infiltrate their village and betray the Smurfs."
Wow.
Not a good look on her.
- She's a Frankensmurf? - Yes.
And her naughty nature took Smurf Village by storm.
She even flooded our village.
The Smurfs wanted her gone,
but even though she was Gargamel's creation, Papa saw the good in her.
With love, kindness, a complete makeover, and a secret magic formula,
he turned her into a true-blue Smurf,
and that is how our darling Smurfette came to be.
- Hi. - Holy moly.
Hi, Smurfette.
I wish I had that hair.
- Nice dive, Smurfette. - That was amazing.
Wow. Show-off.
Pretty!
- That was so purty. - Nice tuck and roll.
- Hi! - Like a beautiful mermaid.
Wait, how is her hair still dry?
Oh, no.
What...
Stupid, trusting Smurfs.
You're mine now.
- It's alive! - Smurf for the hills!
Don't kill the narrator!
The world as we know it is over!
She's got a Dragon Wand.
Don't hurt my cupcake!
Look out!
Yes! My beautiful creation.
You truly are daddy's little girl.
No...
Smurfette, are you okay?
Oh, Papa.
There, there. Everything's going to be fine.
Having that nightmare again?
Papa, every year on my birthday,
I have these horrible dreams about where I come from,
and it makes me wonder who I really am.
And every year, I remind you, it doesn't matter where you came from.
What matters is who you choose to be.
Really?
Don't take this old Smurf's word for it.
Go out there and see for yourself.
This is where you belong.
You belong to Gargamel.
"You belong to Gargamel." Say it.
"You belong to Gargamel."
"I, I."
You know what? Never mind, sir. You're a dim-witted toad.
"You're a dim-witted toad, sir?"
No, actually, you are!
There.
Yet another groundbreaking feat of illusion
from the most innovative conjurer the world has ever seen.
Gargamania,
the magical sensation that has captivated the nation from New York to Las Vegas,
is now taking on the City of Light, Paris, France.
This master mysterio has gone from unknown to unstoppable
after a surprise discovery in New York.
Yo, get out of the road, freak!
How dare you? How dare you call me "Yo"?
Hey, no, put my car down.
Yo, how do you like it up there?
Moron.
From New York street performer to the new toast of Europe,
the only magician ever to play the famed Paris Opera House.
Stay tuned.
Oh, dear gods, can we please just have one quiet carriage ride
without you tormenting me about using up all the Smurf essence?
I extracted all I could from Papa Smurf in the kingdom of New York.
How much essence did you extract?
I'm squandering it?
What are you talking about?
I had to turn that man into a giant toad. It's a magic show, isn't it?
Because without Smurf essence, I can't...
Why am I even discussing this with you? You don't have any magic!
Stick that on your Facebook page and lick it.
Like it. Like it. Whatever.
Besides,
I still have plenty enough essence left to carry out my delightfully diabolical plan.
Now, my adoring public desires me.
Hello!
Hello, my lowly little bootlicks.
Yes, you must all worship me.
Yes.
Even you, my flea-bitten little fur bag.
All hail the great and powerful...
Azrael... Azrael... Stop it.
Open it! Open it!
Come, Azrael. Hurry up.
Hello, handsome.
Look, a present.
No doubt from a worshipping admirer.
It's for you.
You are not more popular than I am.
A little green dot?
Why do you get all the little green dots?
Get it, get it.
Father's going to love this.
- Hackus want to play. - Hey!
Let Hackus play with the kitty.
Cover me.
I'm going in.
Hello, kitty.
Vexy!
All right, my little Naughties.
Yeah!
Hackus to the rescue!
Booyah!
Good save, Hackus.
Pull, pull!
Hackus cat-fishing. Caught a big one.
And round 12 goes to the Naughties.
Well said, my dim brother.
Apparently, it wasn't a gift, Azrael.
It was a trap.
- Very amusing, my little Naughties. - Hey!
Did we please you, Father?
No, no, you didn't.
You know what would please me, Vexy, if you were blue like real Smurfs,
then your essence would endow me with real magic like that of a true-blue Smurf.
That would excite me.
Instead, you're both just deeply disappointing experiments.
Experiment?
Like my traitorous Smurfette.
The banner goes over there, please. Thank you, and I love the pinata.
- How's that, Gutsy? - A little lower, Grouchy.
I want to be able to whack him right in the smurf berries.
Hey, Grouchy. Hey, Gutsy.
What a cake! Smurfette's gonna love this party!
Hey, who smurfed a bite out of Smurfette's birthday cake?
- Not me. - I don't know.
- Greedy? - What? Why you all looking at me?
Hey, Brainy, here's my present for Smurfette's surprise party.
Come on, Jokey, do you really think that I, the smartest Smurf in the village,
- would fall for your sophomoric gag? - Yep.
Just give me the card.
Out-smurfed by a simpleton.
- She's coming. Smurfette's coming. - Oh, no! The surprise will be ruined.
Code blue! Code blue! Repeat, this is not a drill. Code blue.
Undo it, unglue it!
We gotta get her out of here!
Here she is! Act natural!
Hey, guys.
Anyone want to do anything fun on this special day?
Hey, Vanity.
Want to sit by the fountain and look at your reflection?
Kind of tired of looking at myself, Smurfette.
As if.
Nope, not building anything for anybody.
- Hey, Party Planner. - Hey.
- Hey, Social Smurf. - Yes, darling?
Anything fun coming up that I should know about?
No, nothing till Smurfapalooza.
It's going to be wild, right, Social Smurf?
Yeah. I've got it all over the Smurf Web. It's got 101 likes on Smurf book.
I will put you on the guest list.
So, no one remembered my birthday?
The surprise is gonna be ruined!
Hush up! Hush up!
You know, Smurfette, occasionally, it's good to have a little alone time.
- Yeah, so take a hike. - Yeah, we don't need you here, we're good.
- Bye. - There you go.
See you.
We fooled her pretty good, don't you think, Clueless Smurf?
Yeah! She's got no idea about the surprise party!
Dude.
Maybe I really don't belong here.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday to Blue
Okay, blow out the candles, Blue.
Nice.
Okay, I think I've got everyone's issues covered here.
This is an organic, gluten-free, antioxidant-rich acai berry cake
made locally by a cruelty-free baker who swears he's never even seen a peanut.
Everybody good? Right?
- Are these plates PCB-free? - No.
- Actually, we're good. - Actually, we're good. PCB and BPA-free.
Daddy, can we cut the cake?
- Yeah. - All right, let's do that.
Cut it.
Boy, who thought parenting could be so complicated?
- Yummy. - Seriously, guys?
You guys make it look easy.
Yeah, you must have had a great role model.
No, not really.
- My dad took off when I was five, so... - Am I late?
Did I miss all the presents?
Hey!
- Grandpa Vicster! - Hey!
Happy birthday, Blue.
Now it's a party. Hello.
I'm Victor, Patrick's dad.
And you must all be his friends, which makes you my friends.
So let's go.
Arms in the air, you're all getting hugs.
Hey, okay.
I thought you said your father left you.
He did. This is my stepfather.
You'll want him to leave. Just wait.
Hello. Where's my Gracie?
- Hey. - Victor.
How are you?
You know, ever since Blue was born,
I kind of miss you being as big as a house with more of you to hug.
Yep.
And now, I've saved the biggest hug for last.
- Boundaries, please. Boundaries. - Let's show them how it's done.
Unhand me.
I don't like this at all.
Thank you.
There's nothing like the embrace of two proud Doyle men.
I am not a Doyle man.
Little Paddy Doyle.
- Winslow. - Okay, compromise. Winslow.
Hyphen-Doyle.
Hey, isn't he the guy from the Korndog commercials on TV?
- Hey, you're right. - Well, you got me.
- Korndog King. - No, no, no.
- One moment. - Please not this.
Now, in honour of Blue's birthday,
I'm going to present each and every one of you with a free Korndog...
- Thank you. - ...on the house.
Teriaki dog.
That's for you.
Do these have any peanuts?
I would never put peanuts in a Korndog.
Great.
Go ahead, big guy, it's okay.
For the simple reason, you see, we deep-fry them in peanut oil.
Peanut oil?
- What? - Johnny, spit it... Spit it out right away!
Okay, I got the phone, okay.
Spit it out, Johnny! Spit it out right away! Into Mama's hands.
Deep breath for the EpiPen.
- It's okay. - What's happening to that kid's lips?
- Azrael, bring me my plan. - Father?
It's in the bathroom. Check my side of the sink.
Father?
It's feeding time.
Hackus dizzy.
Yes, I almost forgot.
Apparently, I have to keep you alive.
I hope you both appreciate what a tremendous burden this is upon me.
All right, mind your manners.
Thank you.
If you were real Smurfs, I'd be taking essence from you.
I didn't hear a "thank you."
Close enough. Come, come.
We must review my plan before tonight's raid on Smurf Village.
This is not my writing parchment. Where is my plan?
"Gone digital"?
I don't understand what that means.
Yes, phase one, "Create Naughties." Yes.
Check. Where is phase two?
I am enamoured of that swiping motion.
Yes, get away, get away, get away, get away.
Phase three... Swipe.
I capture my ungrateful daughter
and force her to tell me the secret formula that Papa used to turn her blue.
Swipe.
I turn you and hundreds other like you blue.
Hackus blue!
I place you into a terrifying machine and extract your essence.
- What? - And then,
the entire world shall bow before me!
Will that extracting thing hurt?
It's excruciatingly painless.
You'll see, it'll be fun, for me.
Anyway, we're getting ahead of ourselves.
Back to phase two, the very reason we came to this cheese-infested metropolis.
The great iron spire.
The only possible way
to harness enough energy to create a portal right into the heart of Smurf Village.
How I love portal creation.
Come, come, let us away! To the iron spire!
It worked!
Yes! Just enough essence!
And now I will go down in history!
Nothing can stop me now!
My Gargaberries!
Oh, no!
Now I shall prove my genius!
Head spin!
It appears I lack sufficient essence to create a human-size portal.
Father, I can fit through there. Let me get Smurfette.
Hackus go! Hackus go!
- Hey! - Hackus go!
Yes, yes. Well, let's see here.
- Eeny, meeny, miny... - Pick me! Pick me!
Moron.
Yes!
- Hey, Hackus, listen to this. - What?
I win.
Nicely played, Vexy.
Now, I must warn you.
Your destination is a true horror.
A realm filled with the relentless crushing quiet of peace,
punctuated by the wretched cacophony of joyousness.
- It's horrible. - What a nightmare.
Yes, yes, it completely ruined your sister.
It's such a shame when a bad girl turns good.
So true.
But she does know the secret formula,
so go get Smurfette!
I just don't get it.
They know how tough my birthday can be,
and they didn't even remember.
Maybe Papa was wrong.
Guess I'll never really be one of them.
- Oh, no! - Help.
Please, wait.
I escaped.
Escaped?
From the evil wizard who made me.
Do you mean Gargamel?
Is Gargamel your father?
Yes.
But he's...
That means you're just like me.
- Gotcha! - What are you doing?
Father's going to be very happy.
Smurfette's in trouble!
- Crikey! - Oh, no!
- Come on, Smurfs! - Smurfette!
No!
- Oh, no, you don't. - No!
- Let go! - Now get in there!
Oh, no!
- She's being smurf napped. - Unhand her!
So long, Smurfs.
- Smurfette! - Smurfette!
What are we gonna do now?
My powers of deduction lead me to believe that this is the work of Gargamel.
Oh, no, oh, no!
- Yes! - Pretty blue.
Gargamel.
Smurfette. Welcome home.
You're wasting your time, Gargamel.
Papa and the others are gonna come for me.
I don't think so.
They came for Clumsy.
Yes, but you see, Clumsy was a real Smurf.
Whereas I was the one who created you.
You do remember that, don't you, dear?
You're not my father. Just let me go home.
Of course.
Anything you say,
but first, I will need one itsy-bitsy, teeny-tiny little thing first.
- Teeny-tiny. - What?
Just the secret formula that Papa used to turn you into a real Smurf.
Hackus real Smurf. Hackus blue!
Like you, blondie.
It would benefit us both, don't you see, my dear?
You give me the formula, I turn my little Naughties blue.
- Blue. - I use their essence
to continue with my wonderful magic show here.
That way I never have to bother you or Smurf Village again.
I don't trust you, and I'm not telling you anything.
Well, perhaps you need a little persuasion, eh?
Naughties, attack!
With pleasure.
Attack!
- No, no, no, not each other. - Not me!
I got you...
Hackus!
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
Not the cat, not the...
Deeply, deeply disappointing experiments.
We've got to rescue Smurfette.
What's our plan to bring Smurfette home?
All right, Smurfs, listen up.
I saved enough grotto water from the last blue moon for just such an occasion.
I was able to smurf it into smurfportation crystals.
So you don't need a portal. Very clever, Papa.
Smurf-xactly.
These will take us directly to Master Winslow's mushroom.
Yeah, Patrick and Grace helped us last time we smurfed through the portal.
Precisely! They'll know what to do!
- Sign me up! - Sign me up.
- At your service, Papa. - Pick me!
- Did someone say, "Baker should go"? - I would rather not.
Me, me, pick me, Papa!
Now, now, Smurfs. I only had water enough for nine crystals.
That's me and three others round trip, plus Smurfette on the way home.
Assuming you can find her, which you won't.
That's not a very smurfy attitude, Grouchy.
Actually, for me, that was pretty good.
I'll need courage, intelligence and strength.
- So Gutsy. - Aye.
- Brainy. - Of course.
- Hefty. - You got it.
- You'll smurf with me. - Yeah, can I...
Yes, Passive-Aggressive Smurf?
I think Brainy is a really excellent choice.
Good luck with that.
You see what he does?
- That's not a compliment. - Go figure.
- Okay, Hefty, take one. - Let's do this.
- Go get her, guys! - Oops!
Clumsy.
Somebody do something!
Stand back! I know the Smurflich manoeuvre.
He doesn't look good.
Oh, dear, he's turning blue-er.
Not good.
Somebody get my hammer!
Nice going, Clumsy.
I got it!
Cheerio!
This was supposed to be Hefty!
Sorry! My bad!
I get so puffy when I travel.
Bye.
Well, sometimes, you got to smurf with the changes.
Travel safe, Papa.
And so Papa and his B team...
I'll be in charge while you're gone!
- And so Papa... - Go get Smurfette back!
- Come on! - And bring her home!
I'm glad his throat opened up and his lips are back to normal.
Again, we're so sorry.
If... Hello?
Johnny can breathe again, which makes two of us since both of his parents are lawyers.
Well, that's why they overreacted.
They didn't overreact.
He's dying.
I think it's time for this.
You didn't bring the crown. Don't put the crown on him.
Come on, you used to love this crown.
- No, I didn't. - Yes, you did.
- You wore it everywhere. - I did not.
Never did. Never once.
This is the way you do it... Look.
Do you see what is going on out there?
Yeah, they're bonding.
- Technically, they're spitting. - Come on.
Blue needs to know that family's not just you and me,
and it's really good for him to play with his grandfather.
Good job!
- Oh, yeah. He's a terrific role model. - Come on, Patrick.
Grace, he ruins everything.
He shows up, and he ruins things. That's what he does.
Just like when he first moved into my house.
He sent my parrot away.
Your parrot?
My father's parrot.
When my dad took off, he left Zeus, and I loved that bird.
I was a kid, and Zeus was the only part of my dad I had left.
There you go.
What?
Get Blue. Blue?
Blue?
Blue! Victor!
- Stay there. - Victor, do you have Blue?
Victor! We can't get the door open!
Victor!
- Victor, open the door! - Victor, we can't open the door!
I can't see! I can't see!
I'm on a dark, lifeless planet that smells like corn dogs!
Oh, the smurfanity.
Sorry, mister. Your face got in the way.
- Is that Clumsy? Smurfs? - Clumsy?
- Help! - Look out, Grouchy
- Clumsy, is that you? - This way!
- I'm blind! - No, you're in a corn dog.
I knew it would end this way!
Where am I?
This place is strange and terrifying
and so handsome.
Hello, you.
Everyone is ok?
No!
We're lost in the dark, and it smells like corn dogs!
Watch out!
Master Winslow's gotten old.
- Wait, wait, wait. - Blue?
Stop, stop, stop. They're friends.
- Friends? - Yeah.
They're little blue aliens trying to steal our faces.
No, no, they're called Smurfs.
And they are the sweetest little things you ever did see.
Not me.
No, not you, Grouchy.
Papa, Clumsy.
- Patrick! - Master Winslow.
- Hi, Grace. - Smurf, Smurf, Smurf!
- Is that Blue? - He's huge.
I wouldn't want to be the stork that brought that guy.
Well, if Blue likes the Smurfs, then Vicster likes the Smurfs.
What a thrill this must be for all of you.
No pictures, please.
That's Vanity.
Narcissist.
What are you guys doing here?
Smurfette's been taken.
- Wait, what? - Taken? What do you mean "taken"?
Smurf napped by that ghastly Gargamel.
She was off alone because she thought we forgot her birthday.
There was a misunderstanding.
But if we can find him, we'll find her.
Well, that shouldn't be hard. He's a big star now.
- He's in Paris. - I'll call the dog sitter.
You get Blue's passport.
Yes, a rescue mission. I'll come, too.
You need all the help you can get.
Wait a minute, Blue's passport?
We can't just up and go to Paris.
At least, not all of us.
Okay, so that's one vote no. Who votes yes?
- Me. - Of course.
Daddy always loses.
Look, this is my Smurfette we're talking about. We have to go.
If we're going to be traveling, let's make sure we do this properly.
La la la la, Sing a happy song.
Okay, here we are. Victor, can you get Blue?
- All right. We're all clear on the plan, right? - Yeah.
We'll head over to Gargamel's show
- and see if Smurfette's there. - Yes.
And I'll go to Gargamel's hotel and see if I can find out what room he's in.
And, Victor, you and Blue can just check into the room here.
- Well, actually, I was thinking... - No. "Actually, I" nothing.
You and Blue, upstairs.
That's the deal. End of story.
L'Opera House, s'il vous plait.
My French is tres sexy, non?
- Oui, maybe I'll get you a beret. - You cannot handle me in a beret.
- Is that what you think? I can't... - Hey!
Get a shroom.
- Good luck. - You, too.
Okay.
Give him the formula.
You want to give it to him.
You'll feel better about yourself
if you stop being such an annoying little brat and give him the formula.
Make her stop. It burns.
Hackus tell you everything I know.
Hackus doesn't know anything.
What? What?
"Buffering"? What the...
My public awaits.
Once again I must go astound and confound the merry imbeciles.
What do you mean, I'm out of essence?
We can still do the show, all right.
Because we got all the essence we need right here now, don't we?
I'm going to need a little snip.
Oh, no!
Just going to take a little off around the ears.
There.
When my Papa gets here, you're gonna be sorry.
Your Papa is not coming because your real Papa is already here.
- Yeah! - Now,
you can either be a good little girl and give me the formula,
or you can spend the rest of your miserable little existence
being harvested inside my new superpowered Smurfalator!
Your call entirely. Really.
Up to you.
Father! Father!
Yes!
Nice work, my dear.
And as for you, nice try.
Yes, Azrael.
You can press the button on the Smurfalator.
Come, come, come!
We'll brew this hair into Smurf essence!
Papa, please hurry.
I'm so scared.
Poor baby's gonna cry.
Hello, pretty lady.
Hackus pretty, too.
- Hi. - Hello.
I was just wondering if you could be so kind as to tell me what room...
What room Monsieur Gargamel is in?
No. Hotel policy.
Just right over there. Thanks.
Here we are, guys, the Paris Opera House.
- Not too shabby. - Gargamel's really come up in the world.
I hope Smurfette's here.
I do love a good musical. Guilty!
- What did he just say? - I have no idea.
Well, wait a minute, wait a minute.
I asked for a shroud of mystery. This is a wisp!
Alakazatmosphere!
Holy smurf!
- Where did that come from? - He's never had this much power before.
Well, I am outraged!
Positively outraged.
I'm sorry, who are you?
I am Monsieur Gargamel's manager, Madame Doolittle.
What is this outhouse you call a room?
- The Napoleon Suite? - Napoleon Suite? Yes.
But, Madame, this is the finest room in all the hotel.
What could possibly...
Well, for starters, darling, it's on the wrong floor.
No one wants to be on the...
- The fifth floor. - Yes. Yes, that's much too low.
Good evening! Good evening!
Okay, guys, we're going in.
No, no, no.
Great.
Okay, Papa, sneak out the back of my sweater
while I talk to this man who has no idea what I'm saying
and go find that dressing room.
This is a great vacation, guys. I can feel the stress melting right off me.
- Don't spiral, Grouchy. - Yeah. We got this.
- Gentlemen, we have a cat problem. - Get down, get down.
There! No, no, don't be alarmed.
This is how I treat all the critics.
Hurry, up those ropes.
Is Smurfette really worth all this?
- I'm just saying. - Let's go.
- Not permis. Not permis. - What? This is outrageous.
Your families will all pay dearly.
As a result, some of you may die.
No, I'm sorry, you will need your key card.
Yes, of course, darling, my key card!
Oh, dear, I've left it.
Oui, I was having breakfast at Tiffany's.
I'll just go back and get it.
I bet my glutes look great climbing up this rope.
Grouchy, take a look.
I hate my life.
- Clumsy! - Move it.
...Interrupt my sorcery, at least I should be amused.
Now, you will all kindly hail to the great and exceedingly powerful Gargamel...
What are you doing out here? How dare you?
You smell something suspicious? Well, of course you do!
I've seen where you put your nose.
Now, get out of here.
Hi, Daddy.
- Blue? - Yeah, yeah, yeah, just listen...
Blue and I decided we can't let you run solo on this.
We can do this together.
Three generations of proud Doyle men standing shoulder to shoulder.
Even though we're all different heights and whatnot.
We are not Doyle men.
Winslow-hyphen-Doyle.
You have a bee in your bonnet about the whole name thing.
Why do you chortle?
Usually, in magic, the cats are big, no?
Like tiger or like lions, you know?
Silence, knave! And allow me to oblige you.
Alakazanimal!
Try not to smell delicious!
So far, this is the worst trip of my life!
And I've only taken two!
- Look! There's Gargamel's dressing room. - Good eye, Vanity.
Please! He's got a star on his door.
Let's go.
Remind me to put a star on my mushroom when we get home.
- If we ever want to be blue... - Blue.
...we've got to come up with some way to get her talking.
- Yeah. - Got any ideas?
I got it! Say "please."
Never mind. I forgot you were you.
- All right, here's my plan. - Okay.
We trick her into acting like us, being naughty.
Naughty, naughty!
We use all her goodness against her.
Once that happens, she'll feel like she's part of our family!
Family! I like family!
I love this plan!
- Oh, no! - Broken family!
- Get her! - Catch her! Catch Smurfette!
See you later, Smurfigators!
Father's gonna kill us! Go faster!
- Au revoir, trolls! - Get her!
- Hello? - Smurfette?
- Where are you? - Quick question.
How is it we can't reach a doorknob, but we can get up here?
No, Clumsy, don't! No, no!
You just lost a fight to an empty room.
Nobody wants to come up here
and play with the larger kitty that they so annoyingly asked for!
You have to go! Now!
- Yeah, soon as we get the Smurfette. - Yeah!
- He coughs up everything he eats. - You!
Magic man, hand over the Smurfette.
What did you just say?
You heard me.
Give me the Smurfette! Now!
How dare you? Alaka...
- Duck! - ...duck!
Duck?
That was... up.
No!
You.
By great Merlin's beard, I remember you!
We meet again, eh?
Daddy's flying! Daddy's flying!
Well, well, well, it appears we have a volunteer after all!
Enough fooling around, yes? Open wide, Azrael.
Put him down, Gargafella!
Leave my son alone!
I'll teach you to mess with us Doyle ducks!
You again!
What are you doing? Put me down!
Come on, Blue.
Put me down! I could have taken him! I had him!
I'm afraid that's all the show we have time for.
Good bye.
Go on, get out, get out, get out.
Smurfette's hair. She's been here.
Look! I found something.
A portrait of perfection.
Imagine how good you'd look if you were actually helping.
Don't hate the player, hate the game.
- Smurfette? - Smurfette?
Hey, is that coffee?
Anyone else want a cup o' joe?
Hey, what's that?
It's a mirror, you barbarian.
Snap out of it, Vanity, and push!
Rage before beauty.
Whatever this is, it's making my butt scrunch.
That's a little scary. I mean...
Gargamel!
Clumsy! Are you trying to get us smurfed?
It's some sort of magic window.
Maybe it'll show us where Smurfette is.
Naughties?
- Gargamel! - Quickly, pick it up.
Quickly, to me, to me!
Smurfette? Hello?
Where did you go? Hello?
- Move, Smurfs. - Here he comes. Hurry.
- Let's go! Let's go! - Where are you? Are you here?
- Children? Smurfette? - Back up, back up.
Close the door! Close the door!
Your papa is back.
Her papa?
If this is a joke, I assure you I don't find it funny.
- Hello? - Hold it!
- Are you down there, you little delinquents? - Keep still.
They must have retreated back to the hotel.
Of course we're running out of time.
If that Patrick person is here, then Papa cannot be far behind.
Quickly, to the hotel! We must get to her before he does.
My face! My face!
- What? - It's gorgeous.
We fell, and it wasn't even my fault!
Anyone? Anyone?
Oh, my Smurf.
I'm scrunching again.
Papa, what does this have to do with Smurfette?
Everything, I'm afraid.
Why would he build such a hideous device?
Is that a giant Smurfalator?
To extract our essence.
What are all those containers for?
Ninety-nine bottles of Smurf on the wall.
So if Smurfette gives him the formula...
He can turn as many Naughties into Smurfs as his greedy heart desires.
Guys?
Total Smurf a geddon.
Oh, dear.
Need a catch, please.
This place really needs to recycle.
Think, Smurfette, think. Oh, no!
- Where's Smurfette? Where's Smurfette? - There she is!
She's fast! I love this game!
Wait! Let's let her run for a bit. She's got nowhere to go.
- This is perfect for my plan! - Yeah, yeah.
What are you so cross about? I'm the duck!
You always barge in and ruin everything! You're like a walking disaster!
Hey, look me in the eyes and say that.
- I can't. - That's right, because it's not true.
No, I can't because your eyes are on the sides of your head!
All the better for me to see your disrespect!
- What are you looking at? - Hurry up.
It's global warming. Buy a Prius.
Okay. Did I lose them?
Good dog.
No, no... Sorry. Excuse me.
Okay, I got this.
Papa, where are you?
Why am I not surprised the way out of Gargamel's lair is through a sewer?
- Master Winslow. - Papa!
- Patrick, look. - What happened?
Gargamel is hatching a terrible, terrible plan.
What's with the duck?
That's Victor. Gargamel turned him into a duck.
- Now Gargamel knows we're onto him. - I was only trying to help!
Victor, you look fowl.
Yes, I did. Yes, I did.
Focus, everyone. We've got to find Smurfette quickly.
- There she is! Got her! - Chase over?
Hey, Hackus. See that candy store?
- Candy? Candy! - I've got an idea.
Go get yourself in trouble. Be naughty! I'll take care of the rest.
I love to make trouble! Naughty, naughty, naughty!
Hey, blondie. Where you going?
Leave me alone.
You mean like your so-called Papa has?
No, he hasn't!
He will come for me.
He won't, because he knows you're where you really belong.
I didn't kidnap you, Smurfette.
I brought you home.
I'm gonna make big trouble.
Yummy candy!
Here comes trouble!
Hello!
Oh, my gosh! He's gonna be killed! We have to help!
I thought you were supposed to be good.
But...
Help!
Oh, smurf.
Okay, come on!
Oh, no. I'm really in trouble now.
- Vexy! - Oh, no! Hackus!
Help!
Help Hackus.
Smurfette, what are we gonna do?
Vexy, give me a lift! Come on, jump!
- Bull's-eye! - Holy smurf!
- Good one, Smurfette! - Blend that, candy man!
Come on, Hackus!
Vexy, let's go!
Hold on!
Look out!
Nice move, stealing a cart.
I didn't exactly steal it.
- Sorry! - Well, it's not yours, is it?
Naughty, naughty, naughty.
See? You're just like us.
How am I going to get Smurfette to give me that formula, Azrael?
This whole thing just makes me want to...
Cry? No. Flush her down the toilet bowl.
There must be something we can do.
I know you only have a tiny little pea-sized brain in there, but think!
Is it her birthday? Really? Who cares?
A present? A cake?
Be nice to her?
Bribery and flattery to soften her stony little heart, eh?
That's counterintuitive, but that just might work.
I'm so glad I thought of this!
Let's see...
All right, all right.
What kind of gift should I get her?
- Kitty, kitty, kitty! - Hey, fish breath!
Not now, Azrael, I'm trying to think of
a genuine and heartfelt gift that I can deceive that Smurfette with!
I said not now!
Not now! Not now! Not now! Not now! Not now! Not now!
You are walking home.
Cats.
Faster! Faster!
Excuse us! Sorry!
How are we gonna stop this thing?
I don't think that's gonna be a problem!
And she sticks the landing!
- Yummy pudding! - Hackus, it's mud.
Yummy mud!
Take your best shot, cat!
Watch out!
Yes!
- Nice shot! Let's go! - Nice shot! Let's go!
- Come on! - Move it or lose it, Hackus!
Oh, no! Angry kitty! Angry kitty! Run!
Okay, ladies, act pregnant.
- This way, guys! - Faster!
- It's time to get your wings! - Faster!
Quick, get on the storks!
Let's go!
Wait, where's Hackus?
Fly, big stork, fly!
Here comes kitty! Look out!
Come on, Hackus! Let's go!
Yeah!
Hey, look, it's a catfish!
Bye, kitty!
This is amazing!
Stork going backwards! Stork going backwards!
This is so beautiful!
I'm falling! I'm falling!
Smurfette's my hero!
- How did it go? - Couldn't have gone better.
Except that everything was a complete smurftastrophe.
It's Smurfy's Law.
Well, I have some good news.
I borrowed a waiter's outfit for you, complete with a security card for the elevator.
How did you manage that?
Let's just say that the Plaza Athénée laundry room was paid a little visit
by international apparel inspector Mademoiselle Doolittle.
I was like Meryl smurfin' Streep.
Good job, Grace!
Does everyone get a new outfit, or just Patrick?
- Bloody window. - What was that?
That's Victor.
They wouldn't let him through the lobby, so he flew up.
No depth perception.
Grandpa Vicster is a duck!
Gargamel zapped him.
You can change him back, right?
No, but it's a transformation spell.
It'll wear off eventually.
Everybody relax. It's not a problem.
But if you see me lay an egg, it's just between us.
You don't seem too upset about this.
It's not in a duck's nature to get upset.
We like to let things roll off our backs.
Seriously? You seriously just said that?
- I like that. That's very smurfy of you. - Very smurfy.
Why, thank you. See?
The little Santa Claus Smurf appreciates me.
Maybe someday, Patrick, you'll learn to appreciate my smurfy qualities, too!
Okay. I've... There's... You know...
I'm not having this conversation with a duck.
Now I'm catching a cold.
I wish I had a cold.
I've had Hefty's crystal shoved down my throat,
got attacked as a corn dog, fell down a sewer,
and if that wasn't smelly enough,
had to travel by armpit just to find out we're all gonna be extinct!
- Holy smurf, I'm a downer. - You most certainly are.
Grouchy, the only way we'll be extinct
is if Smurfette gives Gargamel the secret formula.
- But Smurfette would never tell. - Of course not.
- Never. - Absolutely not.
Smurfette could never be tricked into being one of them.
Hey, Smurfette.
Did you do this with your sisters back in Smurf Village?
Lots of flying, but I never had a sister.
Well, you do now.
- Want to race? - You want to race me?
You're in trouble now!
- I'm gonna lose you, Smurfette. - Not a chance.
Watch out!
Hold on tight, Hackus.
- Not that tight, Hackus. - Sorry.
Stork fight!
Coming through!
This is insane!
Smurf, smurf, and away.
Hackus, king of world!
You're playing dirty now!
I'm just getting started.
Go, go!
I call that a Crepe Smurfette.
Snails to go?
- Batter up! - Come on!
Hit me with your best shot.
Snailed her!
- You are naughty, Smurfette. - Yeah.
Hey! I've seen that lady before.
She's beautiful.
They've got one of these everywhere.
I'm gonna strangle that duck.
Vic's like a black cloud that follows me around.
Okay, look, I get it.
But you know what, he's here, isn't he?
He shows up.
Yeah, whether you want him to or not.
Okay, I always heard that showing up was 90% of the job.
A lot of fathers don't even do that.
He's not my father.
Well, that's too bad.
'Cause that pretty much leaves you without one.
- Patrick. - All right, guys.
- Come on. - Let's do this!
- I'm gonna stay with Blue. - And Vic.
Okay, Smurfs, off to Gargamel's hotel.
Patrick, there's actually something I'd like to...
No "actuallys."
You're staying here.
That's not what I was even going...
Victor, don't make me pluck you.
- Let's go. - Let's do it.
We're gonna get Smurfette this time, 100% guaranteed.
What did you just say, Grouchy?
You heard it. I'm tired of being Grouchy. I am changing my tune to a happy one.
From now on, lam...
Ready? Positive Smurf.
I sprained my face.
You'll get used to it. Let's go, Smurfs.
- Come on. Come on. - A paper bag. First-class.
- Hurry... - Clumsy!
Good luck, Daddy!
Le chat VIP.
Please, I will take you to your room.
- Front desk. - Listen well, you slack-jawed knave.
Monsieur Gargamel.
I want ale, curds and blistered meats sent into my room in 10 minutes,
or I will turn you into a legless tree sloth.
How was that, Smurfs?
That's not funny, man.
Duck, duck, duck.
Goose!
The security card for the elevator. Patrick needs my help.
When I show up with this, he'll see this black cloud has got a silver...
A silver lining!
Oh, my...
Master Winslow, please.
- You can't get a reservation... - Focus.
That smells delish!
Le bingo.
Okay, guys, listen, when you get to the room, if there's any problems...
- Snot on a half shell. Delicacy. - Sorry, Mr Fish!
You look fried.
Like I said, if there are any problems...
My friend, there are no such thing as problems.
Only smurfitunities.
- You're freaking me out, Grouchy. - Positive!
Of...
Okay, guys, we're in.
Patrick Winslow-Doyle.
Patrick.
- What are you doing here? - Saving your tail feather. Now come here.
I've got something you need for your mission.
Hurry up. There's no time to argue.
- What? - It's the security card for the elevator.
I have the security card.
What is this? This is our room key.
Well, now when you come back, you'll be able to get in.
- No problem. - I can't...
No, no, no, no, no.
You're welcome.
You can thank me later.
How did you get out?
Now, you just put me back down.
Patrick, help!
- We need you for our duck a l'orange. - You want a piece of me?
No, no, no, no! That's not what I meant.
Yeah, it starts with the ducks, and soon, no one's safe!
- Unbelievable. - Patrick!
Master Winslow?
- Patrick! - Where'd he go?
- He disappeared. - Now we're on our own.
- Well... - Hide!
Monsieur Gargamel.
We're smurfed. Plan B, anybody?
I'm struggling to remain positive here.
Monsieur Gargamel?
Room service.
Hello, kitty.
Here is your room service.
- What do we do? - Smurf him with the element of surprise.
Oh, Clumsy!
- Oh, dear. - Now what do we do?
Just act scary.
What?
I'm a scary ghost!
Nice.
Why do so many bad things happen to little blue people?
Positive, positive.
Window! Window! Window!
Oh, no!
Are you smurfing kidding me? You nearly killed...
I mean, look at this view.
If it looks like a duck, quacks like a duck, and smells like a corn dog...
All right, which one of you is Vic?
What, you don't recognise your own father?
- Let's go. - What about my brothers?
We can't just leave them here to be eaten.
You just met them.
This is my flock. I can't just leave them behind.
Come on, if you're game, so am I.
I am covered in filth.
I look like something the cat dragged in!
Come on, it's not that bad.
Although, if I don't... The cat!
- Not the face. Not the face! - Close the lid!
- That was awesome! - Thank you!
Hackus lives!
Vexy, come and help me close the door.
- Thank you, bird. - Bye.
That was crazy.
Bye-bye, birds. I had fun.
Yeah.
- High fours! - High fours!
Hackus, Hackus, Hackus.
It's so nice having another girl around.
What are you doing?
Rm just hugging you.
Haven't you ever been hugged?
Vexy...
- Hackus hug. Hackus hug. - Hackus.
Hackus squeeze!
Hackus.
I'm positive we should just leave him in here.
Thanks.
Hurry. They're probably doing something mean and horrible to her right now.
Yeah, Smurfette needs us. She's probably scared and...
- I love family! - What...
What is she doing?
I think they're hugging.
Papa?
Hackus love to hug.
Hackus.
Smurfette, come on, I got to show you something.
Look at us. Come on, tell me we're not family.
Smurfette!
Over here!
I'm sorry Papa Smurf didn't come for you.
But maybe your place is here with us.
Yeah.
Maybe it is.
Why is she being nice to them?
She's just identifying with her captors. It's classic Smurf-holm syndrome.
No, she thinks we don't care anymore, and they do.
She's confused.
Clumsy, Grouchy, get up there, and help me get this door open.
- That's my daughter in there! - Okay, Papa.
- I'll get on top. - Okay, Grouchy, you jump, I'll pull.
- Come on, we can do this. - Children.
- Gargamel! - Clumsy, don't let go...
Daddy's home.
And consistent with his kind nature, he brought you a present.
Grouchy, get down. He'll see you.
- How are we gonna rescue her now? - Quiet.
I do believe we got off on the wrong foot earlier.
What's happening?
Would you allow me to wish you a very, very happy birthday?
It seems like only yesterday
you were just my little glob of clay and other putrid ingredients.
You remembered my birthday?
Of course I did. We're family.
- What? - But we're her family.
- Families don't forget things like that. - Does she think we abandoned her?
Speaking of which, your little blue step-papa never did arrive, now did he?
Step-Papa?
Why, I am truly sorry, my dear. That must really sting.
I remember when my father threw me down the well for the first time.
The disappointed look on his face
when I finally managed to claw my way out.
Anyway, happy birthday, my dear.
- Happy birthday, Smurfette! - Happy birthday, Smurfette!
- I want to open! Let me open! - No, no, no.
Ugly.
"Bow. Kneel. Worship me."
Yes, delightful rendition, really.
Keep it up, no-neck, I'll turn you into a cross-eyed newt.
Yes, yes, my dear.
Go ahead, take it.
It's a tiny little magical wand of your very own.
Go ahead. It's your birthday present.
No.
Don't do it.
Do you like it?
Silly me. I've forgotten to turn it on.
Here we are.
Yes, there we go.
Yes, go ahead, try it out. Don't be afraid.
- A Dragon Wand. - Oh, dear.
After all, it is your birthright.
How do you know I won't use it on you?
Well...
Because, Smurfette, I am your father.
Search your feelings. You know it to be true.
- She's gonna zap him. - Get him, Smurfette.
Smurfette...
Sing The La La Song.
Sing it!
This is good, right, Papa?
No! She's becoming one of them!
I have always wanted to do this!
We're losing her.
- Yes! Good one, Smurfette. - Your first cat zap.
Look at you. Look at you.
You truly are daddy's little girl.
- Smurfette! - No, Papa! Grouchy, grab him!
- No, Papa, he's gonna see you! - Get him down!
- Clumsy, help, help me get him down! - Papa, no!
Yeah!
No!
Take to the skies, lads. Free at last! Free at last!
- What are you, Martin Luther Wing? - That's it.
Joke it up, funny boy, but I am proud as a peacock to be a freedom flighter.
Oh, no.
What the... is that?
Hang on, Smurfs! Victor's on the way!
Pop your smurf-chutes.
The flying V!
Gotcha.
Okay, don't panic.
That is a lot of white meat.
Now panic!
Me no likey!
That was brilliant.
- He's naked, right? - Everyone okay?
Help me, somebody. Somebody please, let me out!
I have seen unspeakable things down there.
I have been scarred for life.
Where's Smurfette?
- She's... - Where's Smurfette?
We were too late.
Nice going.
Have fun, children. Just remember, be kind to each other.
Will you get away from me, you bumbling moron?
- Where are they? - What?
Smurfs were here? In this room? Why didn't you say so?
Right now!
She must not learn of this.
We must spirit her away from here and get that formula now.
Smurfette, my dear, are you ready to go celebrate?
- Yeah! - Come on, come on. This'll be fun.
We were this close to getting Smurfette back.
I know.
He distracted me at the worst possible moment, Grace.
I would have been in the elevator if it wasn't for him.
Okay, okay, use your indoor voice, and please, Patrick, just breathe.
I want him gone.
- He's your dad. - No, that's one thing he is not.
He's right, Grace. I'm not his father.
His real father left and started a new family.
He's been chewed up about it ever since.
- Excuse me? - As well you might.
But I can't take the brunt of it anymore.
Hey, I never asked for you to come barging into my life, okay?
I didn't ask you to marry my mother or take away Zeus.
Zeus? The pigeon?
The parrot.
My parrot.
Taken away because you were allergic.
I was not allergic to that bird, Patrick.
Yes, you were.
No, I wasn't.
You were.
What?
It got so bad, every day, you were wheezing, coughing.
Your mother and I both knew that it would break your heart
to think the bird had to go away because of you.
You already blamed yourself for your dad.
So I took the heat.
That's a lie. What are you... I'm not allergic to birds.
Okay, tell you what.
Sniff my feathers.
- I'm not going to... - Come on, sniff them.
Truth itches, doesn't it?
Listen to me, Patrick.
I loved your mother with all my heart.
I took care of Jeannette, and I made her happy.
I also chose to love you as my own.
Now, I didn't have to do that.
But you were this little kid, no father, no hope in his eyes, a big hole in his heart,
so I gave you everything I could.
But I'm done, you know?
You don't want it, that's fine.
My last word of advice to you is this...
Will you grow up?
Stop blaming everyone else for your pain.
And whatever you do,
don't teach that beautiful son of yours that love is conditional,
because it is not.
Good bye, Grace.
Bye-bye, Blue.
Grandpa Vicster.
Bye.
Goodbye, Patrick Winslow.
Look at that big wheel.
Come. Come along, my dear.
So this is why they call it the City of Light.
There's a lot of people.
Yes, well...
I prefer to call them "worshippers."
"Worshippers."
Alakakneel!
Bow. Kneel.
Hackus.
- Shall we? - Let's go.
Don't worry. Everyone likes it. He's a celebrity. Come on.
Okay.
Yes, hello. It's me.
- These are my children. - Hi.
- Who's that? - That's my brother.
Hi. I'm Hackus.
Look at that. It's a magical creature.
Hi.
It's my birthday.
Thank you.
- I have a FASTPASS. - Yeah, FASTPASS.
Monsieur Gargamel!
Thank you for keeping our seats warm. Goodbye.
Bye-bye!
Come along, children. Right this way.
Monsieur Gargamel! Monsieur Gargamel!
Let's go!
- Father. - Not now.
It's feeding time soon.
- Not now! - But...
Here we are.
- Our fun is just beginning, eh? - Yeah.
Alakazelevate!
But isn't this lovely, my dear?
And just think,
with your secret formula and my incredible magic,
there's absolutely nothing that we cannot do.
Yeah.
Think of all the fun we could have, Smurfette.
Okay.
Then why are we going so slow?
- Look out! - Yeah!
Isn't this fun?
Decidedly not!
Best ride ever! Smurfette's fun, huh?
Incoming!
Look out! Coming through!
Sorry!
I must have failed her.
Sorry. I was looking for a place to think.
No, no, no, no. It's okay.
I was doing a little thinking myself.
Master Winslow, it's hard for me,
but, well, can I ask you some advice?
I mean, papa to Papa.
It's about Smurfette.
I don't know what to do.
I turned her blue.
I taught her love and kindness.
But the truth is, Gargamel made her.
She's only a Smurf as long as she chooses to be.
But what if she doesn't?
What if she chooses him?
We could lose her.
We may have already.
I haven't done enough.
Are you kidding?
Gargamel just made her, but you,
you made her what she is.
You stepped in and loved her as your very own.
No one asked you to, you just did.
Because you knew she needed that.
And that's a...
That's a pretty special kind of love.
She's way too smart not to see that.
You're right.
We didn't believe in her because she changed.
She changed because we believed in her.
Thank you, Master Winslow.
That was exactly what I needed to hear.
Me, too.
Just a few more bubbles.
How's that?
Sweet Smurf in Heaven, what have you eaten?
It's okay. Every time a Smurf toots, someone smiles.
- Let's go, Smurfs. - Where?
We're getting Smurfette.
But you saw her, Papa.
She's one of them now.
- A horse whisperer? - No!
- A French Socialist? - No!
A Flying Wallenda!
No, she's with Gargamel. Keep up.
I don't care what we saw.
You never give up on family.
Yeah, Papa's right.
Who are you, and what have you done with Grouchy?
Hey, I'm Positive, remember?
All right, Smurfs. Let's get smurfing.
Master Winslow, you coming with us?
Is a Smurf's butt blue?
You tell me.
Grouchy.
- Put it away. - Anybody else?
Okay, then. Out of the tub with you.
- We've got work to do. - Hey.
Let's smurf this mushroom stand. Let's roll.
Yeah, guys, let's do this.
Victor? Hey.
Okay, Master Winslow, we'll split up here.
All right. I'll find the electrical room and cut the power.
And we'll find Smurfette.
And we'll all look fabulous doing it.
Oh, come on.
Team building. Hello!
All right, see you inside. Good luck.
- Come on, guys. - lnto the belly of the beast.
Why are we coming down here, Father?
Well, we are celebrating your long-lost sister's birthday.
Really?
Can't very well end the festivities without
a cake.
I made you your favourite, my dear. Blue velvet.
Cake.
Go ahead. Go ahead. Make a wish, my dear.
Anything your tiny little heart can dream of, and it is yours.
Anything?
But of course.
Yes, well, within reason.
I'm afraid we're on a bit of an essence budget around here lately.
That's why we need the formula, you see.
There she is.
Is that a birthday cake?
We had a birthday cake for her, too.
She just never saw it.
They look like a happy family.
She's not going to give him the formula, is she, Papa?
If she does, it would mean the end of all Smurf kind.
Wait. Even the handsome ones?
- Yeah. - Vanity, you come with me.
Clumsy and Grouchy, go meet Master Winslow.
Victor, what are you doing here?
Grace called me.
She said you might need a hand.
No, no. Victor, wait.
As usual, Grace is right.
I could use some help.
Well, for starters, you might try lifting the sewer cover.
Unless you're planning on fixing the phone lines?
Smurfette, the formula?
Take all the time you need, my dear.
As long as it's very, very soon.
Then we can all be blue. Together.
Hackus blue. Hackus blue.
You see? They want to be blue,
just like their big sister.
Then we could be a real family.
This is something.
A sacred gift entrusted to me.
I'm sorry.
I just, I...
I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
I've given you everything.
Kindness, presents,
a cake with no poison. It's been horrible!
Now, I have had just about enough of this, young lady.
You are going to give me what I want right now!
- The formula! - No!
Yes!
- Father? - What, what, what?
Hackus dizzy.
What's happening to them?
So dizzy.
Don't tell me you actually care for these pathetic creatures.
How sad for you.
And how absolutely perfect for me.
It looks like the power lines run this way.
Let's go! Let's go! We got to get her out of there!
All right, let's do this!
This way, Vanity. Through this pipe.
We have to save her! This could be my moment!
I'm so sorry, my dear. I thought you knew.
Without essence, they cannot live.
- Father. - No.
Please.
No. Vexy.
So dizzy.
- Hackus. - Smurfette.
Give them what you have! Take some from me.
Take some!
Please!
What's the point? You won't give me the formula,
so, well, I might as well just let them go.
Vexy.
You mean you'd let them die?
I can always make others.
Besides, I am not the one letting them die.
You are.
Okay. Okay.
I'll give it to you. Just feed them.
The formula first.
Feed them. Feed them!
Quickly. We have to get in there.
- Dead end! - It's locked!
The formu-la-la-la-la-la-la.
One hopeful thought.
A dab of royal jelly.
Mimosa pollen.
Smurfette.
- Smurfette! - Yes, good girl.
I can hear them, but I can't see them.
Wait! I know.
Papa, look.
- And a drop of mink oil. - I knew it.
Is she giving him the formula?
- Oh, no. - Smurfette.
Help me get this open.
And you must say one loving truth.
- Of course. - There.
That's the formula Papa used.
Now, feed them! Please!
First, we'll see if this works, huh?
Hurry!
- Come on. - Here we are.
Let's go! Let's go!
Pull, Patrick. Put your back into it.
- Come on! - Hey, there's an opening down here.
- Come on, Positive. - Yeah, let's shut 'em down.
One loving truth.
I hope this works.
Hackus.
- Smurfette. Thank you. - Vexy!
Oh, my Smurf, it worked.
- Hackus! - Hackus blue!
Hackus.
Hackus is blue!
We're blue! We're Smurfs!
It worked. All the world is mine!
- I can make my own Smurfs! - No!
We've been betrayed.
Finally, finally.
You're a real boy.
I'm blue.
Now into the machine with all of you.
Father, no.
- No cage for Hackus. No cage for Hackus. - All right, all right.
- In you go. - No cage for Hackus!
- Everybody gets their own room. - Please!
- I failed her, Vanity. - Papa, wait.
I think I can reach that pin.
Good idea, Vanity.
Come on, come on.
Father, please.
Now, don't go anywhere.
You face leaking.
Hackus leaking.
You sacrificed everything just to save us.
I had to.
I care about you.
We're family.
No like leaking.
Hackus like blue.
What a sickening scene.
I'd be completely nauseated if this weren't
the happiest moment of my life!
- Try the lever, the big one. - Get on my shoulders.
Hurry, lads.
Which way do I go?
Try negative. That might shut it off.
Negative? Nah. I'm all about positive.
There.
One small step for a wizard,
one giant leap for... What?
Positive!
Too much smurf berry cobbler.
Grouchy!
Yes, I said you could press the button, didn't I?
I lied. One giant leap for me!
Just got fried.
Hard to put a positive spin on that.
Son of a Smurf!
Hurry, Vanity.
Narcissism is about to save the day.
- Got it! - Smurftastic work.
- I knew it. - Now go.
- What? - Go!
Come, Azrael!
Apparently, we must harness the power of the skies one final time.
Why does this have to be so Les Misérables?
- Let's go. - Look at me, all rough-and-tumble.
I'm like Commando Smurf.
Hooah!
You are right. Commandos are quiet and stealthy.
- There she is! - Smurfette.
Santa!
Papa? You... You came for me.
Well, of course we came for you. You're my daughter.
Was there ever a question?
- No, it's locked. - Go on through.
- We'll find another way. - Okay.
We'll see you in there, Master Winslow. Hurry!
Here.
Hold this!
Papa.
Oh, my dear.
Papa, I gave Gargamel the formula.
But she saved our lives.
Hackus live! Hackus live!
Papa, I let you down.
I betrayed the Smurfs.
I'm so sorry.
Smurfette, life is the most precious thing to protect.
I'm very proud of you.
You... You are?
Seriously? No spanking? No smack to the knuckles?
You forgive her, just like that?
Of course. We rise to the amount of love we're shown,
and we sink only when that love stops.
Hackus leaking again. Leaking again!
Hey, you found Smurfette!
Hello.
Hi.
Oh, no, we don't have much time.
Let's just get the formula back and get out of here. Hooah!
Wait! What about them?
What about them? They kidnapped you.
Yeah, they're Gargamel's.
So was I, but Papa never gave up on me.
So I'm not about to give up on them.
And you thought you weren't a real Smurf.
- Get them out, quickly. - Right, Papa.
Free Hackus!
And then there were seven, eh?
Hello, kitty.
Welcome to the party, Papa!
Look at all this essence.
I love your work. Really, all of you.
In particular, your Blue Period.
My whole body is scrunching!
That's enough, Gargamel.
You have enough.
Yes, yes, but you see, Papa, I want more than enough!
After all, I have to be able to power this!
I call her La Wanda.
You get it? Because it's a wand.
So I called it La... It's very funny.
If you weren't in excruciating pain, you'd be laughing hysterically, believe me.
Whatever will I do with all of this power?
That's right.
I'm going to rule the entire world!
No.
And, Papa,
I want you to know that as my first official act,
I'm going to create a portal
all the way from Smurf Village right here to my Smurfalator,
so you get to be with all of your little smurfy friends.
Forever!
I don't think so, Gargamel.
Hit it again.
- Give it to me. - Hurry.
Hurry, he's going for his wand.
- Just break it already! - I'm too beautiful to die!
For the love of Smurf, use the pointy end!
Don't just stand there yelling at me! Attack!
Yes!
Alaka...
Hackus real boy.
Thrown to the curb again.
Careful, Clumsy!
- Every time! - Sorry.
Really?
High fours!
Is everyone all right?
All smurfy and accounted for.
- Patrick! - Daddy!
- Hey. - Hey, Grace!
Hey.
We did it!
Oh, Grace!
Smurfette.
I've missed you.
I was so worried about you.
Grace, this is Vexy, my other sister.
Well, I guess that makes you my sister, too.
Are you okay?
Is this what happy feels like?
Hello, pretty lady! I'm pretty, too!
And this is Hackus, my brother.
Hackus!
Hackus, this is Grace and Patrick.
- Hello! - And... Your baby?
This is Blue.
You did good, Grace.
He's blue-tiful.
Who this? Who this?
That's Victor.
He's...
He's my dad.
And Blue's pretty fantastic grandpa.
Daddy and Vicster!
Okay. I got it.
I'm really proud of you, Patrick Winslow.
Hyphen-Doyle.
Hyphen-Smurf.
Yeah, guys! Smurf pound.
- Vanity? - Great job! Great job!
- Positive? - Hey, get that thing out of here!
I'm not pounding anything!
I'm Grouchy, and I got a lot of pent-up anger to vent!
Wow, that feels good.
I'm back!
And so am I!
Perfect.
I think most of you know La Wanda...
- Unfortunately. - ...which is a hilarious play on words.
- Smurfette. - Say hello to my enormous friend!
I don't think so, Gargamel!
Yeah!
Wanda! No, La Wanda, no!
Where is the "off" button on this thing?
No, no, no, no.
No...
No, La Wanda! No means no!
This is really, really gonna hurt.
- Bravo, Smurfette! Bravo! - Good job, Smurfette!
That was amazing!
Well, that takes care of Gargamel.
Let's go home, everybody!
- Yeah! - Home!
We still have one small problem.
I've only got five crystals.
Well, I say no Smurf left behind.
Wow, Smurfette.
You are pretty good with that wand.
It's kind of in my blood.
Which used to concern me.
But as someone wonderful once told me,
it doesn't matter where you came from.
What matters is who you choose to be.
That's my girl.
And you're our papa.
Thanks for giving us a new home.
And a new family.
You're a good Smurf, Papa.
You'll be a good one, too.
I'm gonna miss you, Smurfs.
Maybe you can name a corn dog after them.
Now you're talking. We could use blue corn.
Smurf dogs, yum!
Yes!
Well, safe travels, guys.
And smurf back soon.
Thank you once again, Master Winslow.
Miss Doolittle.
Little Blue.
Papa Vicster.
- Goodbye, Winslow family. - Goodbye, Papa.
- Bye-bye! - Toodles!
- Well, let's go, Smurfs. - Bye-bye, Winslows.
I can't wait to see the rest of my family.
Bye, Smurfs!
- Hey, personal space. - Sorry.
Papa, you got Smurfette!
Welcome home, Smurfette!
- Well, looky here! - Yeah, we're back!
- Hi, guys! - This is good.
And some new Smurfs for our family.
Everyone, this is Vexy.
- Great goobaloo! - She's a sassy lassie.
Hi.
- Hi... - Hi, I'm Greedy.
Hi, I'm Greedy. You want to share a cupcake?
- Crikey! - What the hey?
I nearly smurfed myself.
Hackus.
Hackus, these are your new brothers.
I have new brothers!
Squeeze!
Hold on a minute.
Technically speaking,
according to section six of the Smurf Code of Genealogical Legitimacy...
Hey. Just give him a punt.
- This creature cannot... - Hackus punt!
- Yeah! - That kid's got style.
He's one of us.
And so, after waiting patiently to be relevant again,
our heroic Narrator steps back into his leading role
to point out that when last we met,
the entire village was busying itself with preparations for...
Hey, what's with all the decorations?
Happy birthday, Smurfette!
Do you mind? I'm trying to bookend this.
- And so... - Yo, let's kick it.
...as the music unceremoniously drowns out the narration...
This is for my new family.
Oh, no. No, no, no, no, no! Stop, stop!
Help me, Wanda! Help, help me, Wanda!
And where do you think you're going? You are coming with me!
How dare you call me that? I have bungled nothing!
Well, Paris is over, my friend.
We're back here in the Dark Ages. I suggest you get used to it.
You want room service? Why don't you yell out the window?
Don't you show your claws to me unless you are prepared to use them, Mr Pussy Foot!
Pussy foot! Pussy foot! Pussy foot!
Stop it! Not the face! Not the face!
~ Ooh my my baby don't be shy
~ I see that spark flashing in your eye
~ My heart beats fast 'cause I want it all
~ So baby come with me and be my ooh la la
~ Take my hand we can go all night
~ And spin me round just the way I like
~ It feels so good I don't wanna stop
~ So baby come with me and be my ooh la la
~ la la la la la la
~ You don't have to wear no designer clothes
~ Just as long as we're dancing on the floor
~ Fingers in my hair and I'm letting go
~ Tonight
~ So free
~ You know can nobody get down like us
~ We don't stop 'till we get enough
~ C'mon turn it up 'till the speakers pop
~ Break it down show me what you've got
~ Ooh my my baby don't be shy
~ I see that spark flashing in your eye
~ My heart beats fast 'cause I want it all
~ So baby come with me and be my ooh la la
见证奇迹的时刻到啦
我想想
先来点
含羞草花粉
还有百合花瓣
能让精灵精华有更强的活力
除非我的咒语失去了作用
最后再加上 思想的火花
很久以前 在蓝精灵村庄里
住着一群快乐的蓝精灵
他们丝毫也不知道 就在不远处
邪恶的巫师 格格巫
正在策划着一个 邪恶的阴谋
嘿
我说 你们到底想不想听故事了
好吧 大家都安静点吧 音乐家们
- 好吧 好吧 - 谢谢 然后呢
格格巫说
我要创造一个无比神奇的作品
蓝妹妹 潜入他们的村庄 对付那些小精灵们
哇哦
她的样子好可怕哟
- 她肯定是个怪物？- 没错
而且她生性顽把皮整个村子闹得鸡飞狗跳
甚至放水 淹了村子
蓝精灵们都想赶她走
但尽管她是格格巫一手创造的 蓝爸爸却看到了她好的一面
用爱和友善 让她脱胎换骨 用一种神秘的魔法
把她变成了一个真正的蓝精灵
我们亲爱的蓝妹妹就这样诞生了
- 嗨 - 我的天呐
嗨 蓝妹妹
啊 我好喜欢她的头发
- 跳的好 蓝妹妹 - 太棒了
哇哦 炫耀
嘿 蓝妹妹
- 哦 - 完美的屈体转身
- 嗨 - 比美人鱼还漂亮
她的头发怎么是干的？
啊 不
等等…
愚蠢的蓝精灵们
你们跑不了啦
- 她是活的 - 往山上跑
我只是个讲故事的
世界末日来了
她有罗魔杖
不要搞坏我的蛋糕
小心
很好 我可爱的小家伙
你可真是爸爸的好女儿啊
哦 不
蓝妹妹 你还好吧？
哦 爸爸
哦 好啦好啦 一切都会好起来的
你是不是又做恶梦啦？
爸爸 我每年生日的时候
都会做那个关于我来历的恶梦
我 我好想知道我是从哪来的
每一年我都会告诉你 从哪来的并不重要 重要的是
你想成为什么样的人
真的吗？
你不用完全相信我的话
出去转转你自己去看看
你就是属于这里的
你是属于格格巫的
你是属于格格巫的 说呀
我 我…
啊 就这样吧 你这个愚蠢的癫蛤蟆
你这个愚蠢的癫蛤蟆 先生
你才是只蛤蟆
看
另一个突破性 壮举性的幻术表演
来自世界上最创新 前所未有的魔术师
格格巫先生
这股热潮席卷全国各地 从纽约到拉斯维加斯
让整个时尚之都 巴黎 为之倾倒
这位默默无闻的神秘大师
在纽约被发掘之后 一鸣惊人
嘿 别挡着路 怪物
你竟敢对我 大喊大叫
嘿 不 快放我下来
上天的感觉不错吧？
大傻子
从纽约街头的艺人化身为欧洲的新宠儿
格格巫是首位 在巴黎歌剧院登台表演的魔术师
不要走开
噢 我的天呐 我们能不能安静的做一回马车
别再用精灵精华的消耗来折磨我了 好吗？
在纽约 我已经从蓝爸爸那提取了最大的量
阿兹猫 你说说 你提取了多少？
我在浪费？
你在说什么呢？
我必须把那个男人变成蛤蟆 那是魔术表演 不是吗？
因为没有精力精华 我就不能…
我为什么要和你讨论这个问题？你又不会魔法
你可以把这个发表在你的"脸书"个人主页上
发表发表 随便发
我说了
我还有足够的精灵精华继续我那个令人兴奋的心狠手辣的计划
现在 该和我的粉丝们见面了
你们好
你们好 你们这些可怜的马屁虫
尽情的崇拜我吧
是
还有你 满身跳蚤的毛毛球
快向最伟大的魔术师…
阿兹猫 阿兹猫 停下
快打开 打开
好啦 阿兹猫 快点
你好 帅哥
看呐 一份礼物
肯定是我的粉丝送的
呃 是给你的
你不可能比我受欢迎
一个小绿点儿？
你为什么喜欢小绿点
抓呀 抓呀
爸爸会很喜欢的
- 海库斯要玩玩了 - 嘿
让海库斯和小猫咪一起玩玩
掩护我
呀呼 我来了
你好啊 猫咪
好了
好了 我的小调皮
吔
海库斯 来救你了
哦 吔
干得漂亮 海库斯
拉 拉
鱼儿落网啦 个头不小啊
第十二回合 我们又赢啦
说的好 我的傻兄弟
很明显 那不是礼物 阿兹猫
那是个圈套
- 很有意思 我的小调皮们 - 嘿
能让你开心吗 爸爸？
不 这还不够
想知道什么会让我开心吗？如果你们像蓝精灵那样 是蓝色的
你们的精华就会像蓝精灵的精华那样赋予我真正的魔力
那样我才会开心
可惜你们两个 都是令人失望的试验品
我是试验品？
和那个叛徒蓝妹妹一个样
横幅支到那边去 谢谢 玩偶做的不错
- 怎么样 勇勇？- 再放下来一点 厌厌
我希望对着他的关键部位 雷霆一击
嘿 厌厌 嘿 友友
哇 蛋糕好漂亮 蓝妹妹肯定会喜欢这个派对的
嘿 是谁在蛋糕上 偷偷的咬了一口？
- 不是我 - 我不知道
- 蓝蓝？- 干嘛都看着我？
嘿 聪聪 这是我为蓝妹妹的惊喜派对
拜托 乐乐 你真以为我这个全村最聪明的精灵
- 会犯这种低级错误？- 当然
快把贺卡给我吧
这也没高级到哪
-她来了 蓝妹妹 - 噢 不 惊喜泡汤了
蓝色警报 蓝色警报 重复 这不是演习 蓝色警报
放开我 放开
我们得让她离开
她来了 淡定
嗨 伙伴们
有没有人想在这个特殊的日子里 做点有趣的事？
嗨 福福
想不想坐在喷泉边 欣赏自己的倒影？
我已经看腻了自己的模样 蓝妹妹
才怪呢
我现在什么都不想做
- 嗨 策划精灵 - 嗨
- 嗨 灵灵 - 干嘛 亲爱的？
有没有什么 我应该知道的有趣的事？
没有 只有精灵音乐狂欢节
那是个盛大的音乐节 对吗 小灵灵？
哦 是的 我已经在精灵网上公布了 有101个人投了赞成票
门票包在我身上…
看来 没有人记得我的生日
惊喜要泡汤了
小声点 小声点
要知道 蓝妹妹 其实偶尔单独待会 也是很不错
- 就是 你快走吧 - 去吧 这里不需要你
- 再见 - 你去哪儿
再见
我们表演得非常完美 对不对啊 小笨蛋
没错 她根本就没发现我们准备的惊喜
笨蛋
也许 我根本 就不属于这里
祝你生日快乐
祝我布鲁生日快乐
好了 吹蜡烛吧 布鲁
太棒了
好了 我想已经给大家显示过了
这是一个纯绿色 无麸质富含抗氧化剂的阿萨伊桨果蛋糕
是当地的索食大师 蓓蓓亲手做的 她从来就没见过花生
大家都能吃 对吧？
- 这盘子是含塑化剂吗？- 没
- 没问题 很好 - 没问题 绝对不含塑化剂和顺丁烯
爸爸 能切蛋糕了吗？
- 好的 - 好的 开始吧
开始吧
伙计们 养个孩子可真不容易？
- 真好吃 - 行了吧 伙计
你看起来挺轻松的
是啊 你肯定有个好榜样
不 其实呢…
- 我爸爸在我5岁的时候就走了 所以… - 没迟到吧？
还没有开始拆礼物吗？
嘿
- 威斯特爷爷 - 嘿
生日快乐 布鲁
正式开始了 大家好
我是维克多 帕特里克的爸爸
你们都是他的朋友 那也就是我的朋友
来吧
展开双臂 来个拥抱
嘿 好吧
我们都以为你爸爸 离开你了呢
没错 这个是我的继父
你会巴不得他消失的
喔 你好 我的格雷丝呢？
- 嘿 - 维克多
你还好吗？
自从布鲁出生以后
还真怀念你那大肚子的模样大得没法拥抱
是啊
现在 最后的 也是最大的拥抱
- 您别这样 拜托 - 让大家看看
别这样
我不喜欢 这样拥抱
谢谢
道尔家族的拥抱 胜过一切
可我不姓道尔
啊 小帕特里克
- 温思洛 - 好吧 温斯洛就温斯洛
温斯洛·道尔
嘿 那不是在玉米狗电视节目上 很火的那只狗吗？
- 是啊 - 对 就是它
- 好眼力 - 不不不
- 拜托 - 不要这样
既然是布鲁的生日
那我就免费给在场的每人一个玉米狗…
- 谢谢 - 在屋子里的人
酱汁玉米狗
这个给你
这里面有没有放花生？
我从来不往玉米狗里放花生的
嗯 接着
吃吧 大个子 没事
理由很简单 这是用花生油炸的
花生油？
- 什么？- 强尼 快吐 快点吐出来
我来打急救电话
吐出来 强尼 吐出来 快点 吐到妈妈手上
别呼吸 我给你打针
- 还好吧 - 孩子嘴唇怎么了？
- 阿兹猫 把计划书拿过来 - 爸爸？
就在浴室里 应该在梳妆台上
爸爸
我们该吃饭了
海库斯头晕
我差点给忘啦
我还得养活你们两个
希望你们能知道 这对我是个多么沉重的负担呐
嗯 好了 要注意礼貌
谢谢
如果你们是真的蓝精灵 就能从你们身上提取精华了
你好像还没说"谢谢"
就当是吧 好了 过来
我们要在今晚突袭蓝精灵村庄前再重温一遍计划
这根本不是我的手稿 我的计划书呢？
这是电子版的
不明白是什么意思
是的 第一步"制造调皮鬼" 是的
完成 那第二步呢？
喔 看起来很有意思
让开让开 快 快点让开
第三部 呃 划一下
抓住我那个不听话的女儿
逼她说出蓝爸爸把她变蓝的那个神秘秘方
划一下
我要把几百个调皮鬼都变成蓝精灵
海库斯变蓝
然后把你们放进一个恐怖的机器里提取精华
- 什么？- 最后
全世界的人都将臣服于我
那提取过程会很疼吗？
那是非常的疼
你会看到那是非常有意思的
对我来说太远的事就先不说了
回到第二部 我们来到这个充满奶酪的大都市的终极目标
就是这个高高的大铁塔
这是控制足够的能量
从而打开通往蓝精灵村庄中心的大门的唯一可行方法
我可等不及了
快跟我来 去占领大铁塔
起作用啦
太好啦 精华正好够用
现在 我将被载入史册
没有什么阻止我
我的鸽子蛋呐
噢 不
现在给你们展示一下我的才华
头在旋转
看来想打开通过人类的入口我的精华还不够
爸爸 我正好能通过 我去把蓝妹妹抓来
我也要去 我也要去
- 嘿 - 我也要去
好吧 好吧 看看到底 该让谁去呢？
- 到底谁是大傻瓜 - 选我 选我
月亮
哦吔
- 嘿 你过来听我说 - 什么？
我赢了
你做得很好 维克茜
现在 我必须警告你
你的目的地是一个非常恐怖的地方
那是个到处都充满了残忍的 宁静王国
偶尔还能听到一些讨厌的刺耳的欢声笑语
- 很可怕 - 真是个噩梦
是的 那地方彻底毁了你的姐姐
坏女孩变成了好女孩 真让人遗憾
说得对
但是她知道那神秘的配方
所以 去把蓝妹妹抓回来
我真是想不明白
他们明明知道我今天过生日
竟然没有一个人记得
爸爸错了
我永远都不能真正的融入他们
- 啊 不 - 救命
求求你 别走
我是逃出来的
逃出来的？
从那个邪恶的巫师制造我的人那里
你说的是 格格巫？
格格巫是你的父亲吗？
是的
但是他…
就是说 你和我是一样的
- 抓住你了 - 啊 你干什么
爸爸一定会很高兴的
蓝妹妹有麻烦了
- 不 - 哦 天呐
- 快过来 蓝精灵 - 蓝妹妹
啊 不
- 你逃不掉的 - 啊 不 放开我
- 走吧 - 进去吧
不…
- 她被人抓走了 - 不
再见 蓝精灵们
- 蓝妹妹 - 蓝妹妹
我们现在怎么办？
我的推理能力明确的告诉我 这件事绝对是格格巫的主意
哦 不 不
- 吔 - 好漂亮的蓝色
格格巫
蓝妹妹 欢迎回家
你这样做是没用的 格格巫
蓝爸爸会带他们来救我的
我可不这么认为
他们曾经救了笨笨
是的 但别忘了笨笨是一个真正的蓝精灵
要知道 我才是制造你的那个人
你一定要记忆深刻 对吗 亲爱的？
你不是我爸爸 赶快让我回家
当然
你怎样想都行
但是 首先我需要一点点东西
- 非常小？- 是什么？
就是 呃 蓝爸爸用来把你变成真正蓝精灵的那个神秘的配方
我要成为真正的蓝精灵 我要变成蓝色
像你一样 小黄毛
这对我们大家都好 难道你不明白吗 我的小宝贝？
你把配方给我 我把我的调皮鬼们变成蓝色
- 蓝色 - 我们可以用他们的元素
继续在这里表演我的精彩魔法
这样 我就不会再打扰你们蓝精灵村啦
我不会相信你 我不会告诉你任何事情
好吧 看来你是不见棺材不落泪咯
调皮鬼们 攻击
乐意效劳
攻击
- 不是互相攻击 - 不是打我
抓到你啦
海库斯
小猫咪 小猫咪 小猫咪
别打猫咪
真是相当相当失败的 试验品
我们要去救蓝妹妹
我们的营救计划是什么？
好了 精灵们 都听着
自从上次出现蓝月我就是在那个时刻存下来 足够的石谷水
我可以把它炼成 精灵传送水晶
啊 那你就不需要传送通道啦 真聪明啊 爸爸
你说对了
这样我们就能够直接进入到温斯洛先生的房子里
对 上次还是帕特里克和格蕾丝 帮我们进去的呢
是这样的 他们知道怎么做
- 我要去 - 我也要去
- 随时待命 爸爸 - 选我
- 有没有人说 贝贝也想去 - 最好不要选我
我 我 还有我 爸爸
安静 孩子们 我存的石谷水 只够做出9块水晶
所以我只能带3个人回来 再加上一个蓝妹妹
前提是能找到她 但很渺茫
这可不是一种积极的态度 厌厌
事实上 这对我来说 已经够好
我需要勇气和智慧 还有力量
- 所以勇勇 - 哎
- 聪聪 - 没问题
- 健健 - 听到
- 你们和我一起去 - 呃 我能…
说吧 消极悲观的小精灵
我认为聪聪可真是一个很棒的选择
祝你们好运
他这是怎么了？
-这可不是他的风格 - 这很正常
- 好了 健健你拿一个 - 我们行动吧
- 让一下 - 糟糕
笨笨
快点救他
快让开 我知道怎么救被噎住的人
他看起来糟糕透了
天呐 他的脸都变蓝了
不太妙
把我的水晶还我
干的漂亮 笨笨
我抓住啦
再见
这块应该是给健健的
抱歉 都怪我
长途旅行会让我全身浮肿的
再见
好吧 有时候你需要学会 随遇而安
一路平安 爸爸
蓝爸爸 带着他那不靠谱的队伍
我会帮你看好家的
- 蓝爸爸带着… - 把蓝妹妹救回来
- 够了 - 带她回家
很高兴他呼吸通畅了 而且嘴唇也恢复了正常
再一次表示抱歉
然后… 喂？
强尼呼吸正常了 谢天谢地 他父母可都是律师
难怪那么大惊小怪的
那不是大惊小怪
它不行了
我们应该玩这个
你怎么把王冠带来了 不用给他戴这个
你以前很喜欢戴的
- 我没喜欢过不 - 不 喜欢过
- 你走哪都戴 - 才没有呢
没有 从来没有
你一向都这样…快看
你看他们在干什么呢？
在联络感情
- 他们那是在吐口水 - 好啦
布鲁需要知道 家庭成员不只我们两个
多跟爷爷相处 对他没什么坏处
干得好
- 是吗 他是一个很糟糕的榜样 - 好了 帕特里克
格蕾丝 他就是个破坏大王
他能做的 就是搞砸一切 仅此而已
就像 他第一次来到我家
就把我的鹦鹉送人了
你的鹦鹉？
是我爸爸的鹦鹉
离开我们的时候 留下的宙斯 我很喜欢那只鸟
我当时还是个孩子 宙斯我父亲给我留下的唯一的东西
你去那里
怎么了？
小心孩子 布鲁？
布鲁？
布鲁 维克多
- 待在这 - 维克多 布鲁怎么样？
维克多 门怎么打不开
维克多
- 维克多 快把门打开 - 维克多 我们打不开门
我看不见了 我看不见了
我到了一个黑暗的 荒凉的 闻起来有股玉米热狗昧道的星球上
这简直太恐怖啦
抱歉先生 你的脸挡了我的路
- 好像是笨笨 蓝精灵？- 外星人？
- 救命 - 注意 厌厌
- 笨笨 是你吗？- 这边 这边
- 我看不见啦 - 你钻进了玉米热狗袋子里了
我知道这次会送命的
这是哪？
这里怎么这么陌生 这么恐怖？
好帅呀
你好 帅哥
大家都还好吗？
这不好
这里一片黑暗 而且还有一股玉米热狗昧
小心
温斯洛先生已经老啦
- 等等 等等 - 布鲁？
不不 停下 快停下 他们是朋友
- 朋友？- 对
小外星人想要把我的脸偷走
不 不 他们是蓝精灵
他们是你见过的 最友善的生物了
除了我
对 除了你 厌厌
蓝爸爸 笨笨
- 帕特里克 - 温斯洛先生
- 你好 格蕾丝 - 精灵 精灵 精灵
- 他就是布鲁吧？- 个头可真大呀
幸好不是我引领他 降生人世
好吧 既然布鲁喜欢他们 那维克多也喜欢他们
真像坐过山车一样 惊险刺激
请不要对我拍照
他叫福福
是个自恋狂
你们来这干什么？
蓝妹妹被带到这来了
- 等等 什么？- 带？什么叫带？
蓝妹妹被该死的格格巫给绑架啦
她当然落单了 以为 她认为我们忘记了她的生日
那是一个 不该发生的错误
如果能找到格格巫 就会找到她
呃 这不太难 他现在是大明星
- 他现在在巴黎 - 我去找人看狗
你负责布鲁的护照
超棒 营救蓝精灵的任务 我也要去
我也去 多一个人 多一份力量
等一下 布鲁的护照？
总不能这样说走就走吧？
至少 不能全都去
好吧 你算是一个反对票 谁投赞成票？
- 我 - 还有我
爸爸就没赢过
听着 事关我的好朋友蓝妹妹 必须得去
如果确定要行动 那我们就应该有一个周密的计划
啦啦啦啦啦 唱支快乐歌
好了 我们到了 维克多 能抱一下布鲁吗？
- 好了 计划都清楚了 对吗？- 是的
我们到格格巫演出的地方
- 去找蓝妹妹 - 对
我去格格巫住的宾馆 想办法确定 他住的哪间房
维克多 你和布鲁在这里登记订个客房
- 事实上 我在想 - 不 事实上你不用做任何事
你和布鲁上楼去
就这么定了 快去吧
去歌剧院 不错嘛
我的法语说的很性感 对吗？
- 我再给你买顶便礼帽吧 - 你无法抵档我的性感的魅力
- 我无法抵挡你的魅力 - 嘿
去开房吧
- 好运 - 小心点
好的
你 把配方给他吧
把配方给他吧
你想把配方给他
给他配方 再也不当捣蛋鬼
这会让你很舒服的 快把配方给他吧
坏丫头 别唱了
我要把我知道的 都告诉你
可是我什么都不知道
怎么啦 怎么啦？
"缓冲"？搞什么呀
观众在等着我
我要让这些傻瓜们再一次为我疯狂
担心精华不够用的是吗？
完成表演绝对没问题
因为 我们现在想要多少精华就有多少 难道不是吗？
我需要稍稍取一点
不
就剪耳朵边的一点好吗？
这里
等我爸爸来了 你会后悔的
你爸爸是不会来的 因为你真正的爸爸 就站在这了
- 没错 - 现在
你是想做个乖女儿把配方给我呢？
还是想在我最新型的超级精华提取器里
凄凄惨惨的度过你的下半生？
我劝你一定要想清楚
你自己来决定
爸爸 爸爸
是
干得好 亲爱的
至于你嘛 也不错
阿兹猫
你可以按下提取器的按钮啦
过来 过来 过来
我们把这些头发 转化成精灵精华
爸爸 快点来吧
我好害怕
可怜的娃娃要哭了
你好哇 漂亮的女士
巫师啊 上场了吧
- 嗨 - 您好
不知道您能不能好心的告诉我 是哪一间？
是格格巫先生的房间？
不行 这是规矩
就停那吧 我们到了 谢谢
我们在这里 伙计们巴黎圣母院
- 简直太壮观了 - 格格巫现在混得确实不错
希望蓝妹妹就在这里
我喜欢听好听的音乐 惭愧
- 你听在说什么？- 不知道
等一下 等一下
我说过 出场时烟雾要大一点 这烟雾也太少了
阿拉塔（咒语）
神圣的蓝精灵
- 他是怎么做到的？- 他比以前强了不少
我现在很生气
我现在非常生气
我很抱歉 您是谁？
我是格格巫先生的经理人 名字叫多莉特
就这种条件 你们也敢叫豪华客房？
- 拿破仑套房？- 拿破仑套房？
但是女士 这是我们酒店最好的套房
您对哪不满意
那我就说说 首先 楼层就不好
没人喜欢住在…
- 住在第五层 - 是的 那实在是太低了
晚上好 晚上好
好了 伙计们 该进去了
不不不
很好
好 爸爸 从我的毛衣里出来
趁着我跟这个大傻子胡说八道的时候
从我衣服溜出来 然后进去这化妆间
简直像度假一样 这可真是一个减压的好方法
- 别垂头丧气的 厌厌 - 对 会成功的
- 哦 先生们 先解决猫的问题吧 - 下来 下来
大家不必惊慌
对待评论家们 我向来是这样
顺绳子爬上去
为了救蓝妹妹 这样值得吗？
- 这是任务… - 快走吧
- 对不起 先生 这是规定 - 什么？太让人气愤了
你们的家人将付出沉重的代价
你们中 会有人死掉
不 很抱歉 需要刷您的房卡
是的 当然 亲爱的 我的房卡
哦 天呐 不见了
我早上去吃过早餐在蒂芬妮
我得去那 找找看
我打赌爬绳子会让我的屁股上的肌肉很有型
厌厌 你看看嘛
我讨厌这样
- 嘘 - 噢 快点
你要打断我的魔法 最起码要逗我开心
现在 你们可以热烈欢迎最伟大的 魔法不灭的格格巫
你来这里做什么 你怎么敢这样？
你闻到了可疑的气昧 你当然会闻到了
我天天看你闻你自己
别在这捣乱啦
嘿 爸爸
- 布鲁？- 嘿 你先听着…
布鲁和我决定了 不能让你一个人 面对危险
我们应该齐心协力
道尔家族应该祖孙三代并肩作战
撇开我们所有的分歧
我们和道尔家族没有关系
你叫温斯洛·道尔
你就是不肯正确面对姓氏问题
停 你们为什么要笑？
通常在魔术中 猫都很大 不是吗？
像是老虎 狮子之类的
安静点 混蛋 我会让你如愿以偿的
阿拉塔 猫来啦
千万别让他发现我们
这是我人生当中 最糟糕的旅行
我也就旅行过两次
- 看 格格巫的化妆间 就在那 - 眼神不错啊 福福
门上居然贴个五角星
走吧
回去我也要在房子上贴个五角星
- 如果我们想要变成蓝色 - 蓝色
我们就必须想个办法 让她开口说话
- 对 - 想出办法了吗？
我想到了 "求"她说
算了吧 我忘了你是头猪
- 好吧 听听我的计划 - 好的
想法让她变成跟我们一样的捣蛋鬼
捣蛋 捣蛋
就利用了她的优点了 对吧？
一旦成功 她就会觉得跟我们是一家人
一家人 我喜欢一家人
我喜欢这个计划
- 噢 不 - 破碎的家庭
- 抓住她 - 抓住她 抓住蓝妹妹
再见了 捣蛋鬼们
父亲会杀了我们的
- 在家 丑八怪 - 抓住她
- 有人吗？- 蓝妹妹？
- 你在哪呢？- 快问快答
抢答题 在够不到门把手的情况下 我们怎么才能进去呢？
不 不 不
一个空空的房间 居然就把你给干倒了
有没有人想要上来
和这个 某些人强烈要求出现的大猫咪
走 快 走
- 找到蓝妹妹 我们马上走 - 对
- 万一被吃掉了 也可以吐出来 - 你
变魔术的 交出蓝妹妹
你刚才说什么？
没听见吗？
把蓝妹妹叫出来
你竟敢这样 阿拉塔…
- 鸭子 - 鸭子
鸭子？
这下完蛋了
不
你
冲着伟大的美丽胡子发誓 我记得你
布鲁 我们又见面啦
爸爸飞啦 爸爸飞啦
看起来终于有一个志愿者啦
那就别再浪费时间了 张大嘴 阿兹猫
放他下来 你这混蛋
放下我的儿子
你敢惹道尔家族的人 你就死定了
又是你
你在干什么？放我下来
快走 布鲁
放我下来 我可以抓到他
今天的表演到这就结束了
再见
走吧 走吧 走吧
蓝妹妹的头发 她来过这里
看呐 我发现了什么
一个相当完美的肖像
如果你真能帮上忙 那该有多好
不要讨厌我 憎恨游戏吧
- 蓝妹妹？- 蓝妹妹？
嘿 这是咖啡吗？
有人想来一杯咖啡吗？
嘿 这是什么？
是一面镜子 你这个白痴
振作起来 使劲 快来推啊
坏脾气比帅哥优先
不管这是什么 都让我感到非常紧张
吓了我一跳 我的意思是…
格格巫
笨笨 你想要我们的命吗？
这应该是一种魔法窗口
也许能看到蓝妹妹在哪里
调皮鬼们
- 格格巫 - 快逃走 快
好的 这边 这边
蓝妹妹？呃？
跑哪去了？呃？
- 快点伙计们 - 在这里 他来了 快点
- 快点走 快点走 - 哪去了？
- 孩子们？蓝妹妹？- 去后面 快快快
关门 快关门
你爸爸回来啦
她的爸爸？
我可不喜欢你跟我开这种玩笑
- 你好？- 是在下面吗
- 你下来 你们这些小罪犯 - 站着别动
他们肯定是回到酒店去了
我们实在是没有时间了
如果那个帕特里克在附近 那么蓝爸爸肯定也在附近
快点去酒店 必须在他之前找到蓝妹妹
我的脸 我的脸
- 怎么了？- 跟以前一样帅
我们摔倒啦 不是我的错
有人吗？有人吗？
我的天呐
我的屁股好疼口阿
爸爸 这些跟蓝妹妹有什么关系吗？
所有东西都有关系 我真害怕
为什么要建立这样吓人的设备？
那个超级蓝精灵机器？
用来提取我们的精华的
这些东西 是干什么用的？
是用来大量囚禁蓝精灵的
蓝妹妹要是把配方给了他
他可以把无数的调皮鬼 变成蓝精灵 来满足他贪婪的野心
伙计们？
上面写着 大决战
天呐
快扶我一下 拜托
这地方的垃圾该收一收了
想想 蓝妹妹 想想
- 蓝妹妹在哪 她在哪儿？- 她在哪里
我喜欢这个游戏
等等 我们让她跑一会 她没有地方可以去
- 这对我的计划很有帮助 - 是啊 是啊
是我变成了鸭子 你生什么气？
你总是横插一脚 把事情搞砸 你到了哪就乱套
看着我的眼睛再说一遍
- 我做不到 - 那就对了 因为那不是真的
不 我做不到是因为你的眼睛 长在脑袋两边
这样让我更能看出你对我的不尊敬
- 你们看什么看？- 你快点走吧
天气变暖啦 普利斯
终于甩掉他们了吗？
好狗狗
哦 不不… 对不起 打扰了
好吧 我能行的
爸爸 你在哪呢？
为什么我对通过下水道离开 格格巫的老窝 一点都不奇怪呢？
- 温斯洛先生 - 蓝爸爸
- 帕特里克 - 怎么回事？
格格巫设计了一个非常可怕的计划
哪来只鸭子？
那是维克多 格格巫把他变成了一只鸭子
- 肯定知道计划已经泄密了 - 我是想 来帮忙
维克多 你看起来像家禽
好的 我知道了 我知道了
别闹了 都听我说 我们一定要尽快找到蓝妹妹
- 她在那 那 - 追上去吗？
嘿 海库斯 看见糖果店了吗？
- 糖果 糖果 - 我有个主意
你去糖果店找麻烦 使劲捣乱 剩下的我来处理
我最制造麻烦 捣乱 捣乱 捣乱
小黄毛 你要去哪啊？
用不着你管
看样子 你所谓的爸爸不要你了
不 才不是呢
他会来找我的
不会的 因为他知道 你回到了应该在的地方
我没有绑架你 蓝妹妹
我是带你回家
我要制造一个大麻烦
美味的糖果
麻烦啦
你好
噢 我的天呐 他会被杀掉的 我们得去救他
我认为你应该是个善良的人
但是…
救命啊
天呐
好吧 我们走
不 我已经陷入麻烦啦
- 维克茜 - 噢 不 海库斯
救命
救救我 海库斯
蓝妹妹 我们该怎么办呢？
维克茜 帮我一下 快点跳
- 漂亮 - 神圣的蓝精灵
- 身手不错 蓝妹妹 - 尝尝这个 很好吃
快走 海库斯
维克茜 快上车
抓紧啦
小心
不错嘛 偷了辆小车
我没有想要偷车
- 对不起 - 好吧 这不是你偷的 对吧？
捣乱 捣乱 捣乱
你和我们是同样的
我该怎么让蓝妹妹把配方交给我呢 阿兹猫？
她的态度真让我特别想…
哭？不 我想把她扔进马桶冲走
一定要想个好办法
尽管我知道你的脑袋只有豌豆那么大
是她生日？真的？管我屁事
送礼物？送蛋糕？
糖衣炮弹？
通过贿赂和恭维来软化她那颗 石头一样的心
有点不合套路 但没准还真能管用
我居然能想出这么好的主意
让我想想
好了 好了
该送她什么礼物呢？
- 猫咪 猫咪 猫咪 - 嗨 大笨猫
安静点 阿兹猫 我正在想 送什么样的礼物
能显得既真诚又贴心 好搞定那个蓝妹妹
我说 不是现在
不是现在 不是现在 不是现在 不是现在
你自己走回去吧
猫咪
快点 再快点
抱歉 让开
怎么停下这东西啊？
我不认为这是个很难的问题
尽在掌握中
- 美味的布丁 - 海库斯这是泥巴
美味的泥巴
有本事来抓我呀 臭猫
小心
吔
- 漂亮 我们走 - 漂亮 我们走
- 快走 - 快跑 海库斯
哦 不 大笨猫 大笨猫 快跑
女士们 换个姿势
- 跟我来 伙计们 - 快点
- 快飞起来 - 快
快骑到鹤身上 快上
我们走
等等 海库斯在哪儿？
飞吧 大白鹤 飞吧
猫咪来了 小心
快上来 海库斯我们走
吔
看呐 漂亮猫咪吔
再见了 小猫咪
真是太奇妙了
大家往后飞 大家往后飞
真是太漂亮啦
我掉下来啦 掉下来啦
蓝妹妹是我的英雄
- 情况怎么样？- 好得一塌糊涂 好的所有的事情
好到所有的事情都变成了彻底的灾难
简直是注定的
我倒是有个好消息
我给你借了一套服务员的制服 还有一张电梯卡配套来的
这些是怎么弄到的？
我到雅典娜广场的洗衣房 骗他们说
我是国际服装督察官 杜丽特小姐来检查工作
比梅里尔斯普演得还像
干得漂亮 格蕾丝
是每个人都有新衣服 还是只有帕特里克有？
- 窗户 - 那是谁？
是维克多
酒店前台不让他进来 所以只能飞上来
缺乏纵身感
维克多爷爷是鸭子
是格格巫施的魔法
你能把他变回来 对吗？
不 但这咒语的效力不常
最后会自己失效的
大家别走这么严肃嘛 这根本不是问题
我看见我生了蛋 还请各位保密
你看起来好像没觉得苦恼
苦恼这两个字 和我鸭子根本就不粘边
抖抖身上的羽毛 身上的烦恼就全没啦
真的吗 你真是这么认为的？
- 我很欣赏 这和我们蓝精灵很像 - 非常蓝精灵化
谢谢 看见啦？
这个小圣诞精灵都非常欣赏我
也许有一天 帕特里克 你也会学会欣赏我这种蓝精灵的品格
好吧 我 这个… 算了…
我不想跟鸭子讨论这个问题
我好像感冒啦
我也希望我感冒啦
健健的水晶飞进我的喉陇
被当成玉米热狗袭击 掉进下水道
如果还不够难闻的话
还被夹在腋下外出 仅仅因为我们快要绝种啦
- 我的天呐 我是个悲观者 - 而且是百分之百
厌厌 我们可能绝种的唯一原因
就是蓝妹妹把秘密配方交给格格巫
- 但是蓝妹妹绝对不会那么做的 - 当然不会
- 永远 - 绝对不可能
蓝妹妹永远都不可能欺骗我们大家的
嘿 蓝妹妹
你在蓝精灵村庄也和姐妹一起玩过这个吗？
经常玩 但是 我一个姐妹都没有
好了 现在有了
- 想比赛吗？- 你想跟我比赛？
那你听好了
- 我要甩掉你了 蓝妹妹 - 不可能
让路
抓紧了 海库斯
- 别这么紧 海库斯 - 对不起
落阵仗
飞过去
真是太疯狂了
飞吧 飞吧 尽情的飞
海库斯乘鹤之王
蓝妹妹 你玩赖
这还是刚刚开始呢
快 快
这个叫做平锅 蓝妹妹
再加上点蜗牛？
- 主动进球 - 来吧
使出你的绝招
两发全中
- 你很顽皮啊 蓝妹妹 - 吔
嘿 我好像见过这位女士
她可真漂亮
不管走到哪 都能看到这个
真想掐死那只鸭子
维克多就像我头顶上的乌云
好了 听着 我理解
但你要知道 他就在这里
无法回避
对 无论你是高兴还是不高兴
好吧 都说父母的出现 是给孩子最棒的礼物
可是很多父亲却做不到
他不是我的父亲
好吧 那太糟糕了
那意昧着 你就没有父亲啦
- 帕特里克 - 好了 伙计们
- 出发了 - 开始行动吧
- 我和布鲁在家 - 还有维克多
好的 孩子们 出发去格格巫的酒店
帕特里克 实际上 我有一些话想跟你说
没有实际上
你待在这
我想说的不是…
维克多 别逼我 拔光了你
- 我们走 - 行动吧
我们一定要把蓝妹妹带回来 百分之百成功
你刚才说什么 厌厌？
你听见的 我厌倦了总是消极 我正在改变我的态度 变得积极
从现在开始 我就是…
预备？快乐的蓝精灵
我的脸好像抽筋了
慢慢就会习惯的 走吧 孩子们
- 好了 快点 - 是个纸袋 头等舱
- 快点… - 噢 笨笨
祝你好运 爸爸
一只尊贵的猫
来吧 我带你去 你的房间
- 你好 前台 - 给我听好了 你这个傻瓜
格格巫先生
我要啤酒 饮乳 熟肉 在10分钟之内送到我的房间
要不然我就把你变成一只没腿的树獭
怎么样？蓝精灵们？
这一点也不好玩
鸭子 鸭子鸭子
天鹅
电梯的安保卡怎么会在这 得去帮帮帕特里克
等他见到我的时候就会明白我这边乌云可是…
向赢边的
噢 我的…
温斯洛先生 别这样
- 这里很难订位置的… - 专心点
哦 闻起来真香啊
真巧
好了 伙计们 听着 进入房间的时候 如果有什么问题…
- 到处都是粘液 真恶心 - 对不起 鱼先生
脸都红了
我说过了 如果遇到什么问题…
朋友 绝不会有哪怕一丁点的问题
反倒是有无限的机遇
- 你吓我一跳 厌厌 - 是乐观
好吧…
好了 伙计们 进来了
帕特里克 温斯洛到了
帕特里克
- 你在这里做什么 - 我来帮你脱险
我这里有你需要完成任务的东西
快点 没时间争论了
- 什么东西？- 是乘坐电梯用的安保卡
电梯的安保卡在这
这是什么？这张是我们的房卡
等你回来的时候就能进来
- 决定没问题 - 我不能…
不不不不…
别客气
不用急着感谢我
哦 你是怎么跑出来的呢？
你快把我放下来
帕特里克 帮帮我
- 客人还等着吃烤鸭呢 - 要切了吗？
不不不不 那可绝对不行
你现在能杀鸭子 以后肯定会杀人的
- 真是难以置信 - 帕特里克
温斯洛先生
- 帕特里克 - 他去哪了？
- 他不见了 - 我们只能靠自己
- 好吧… - 藏起来
格格巫先生
这样麻烦了 还B计划吗？
我正在努力保持着乐观
格格巫先生？
客房服务
你好 小猫
你的客房服务到了
- 现在怎么办？- 突然袭击 出其不意
等等 笨
- 哦 天哪 - 现在该做什么？
装出很吓人的样子
什么？
我是个恐怖的精灵
漂亮
为什么蓝色的小精灵能够经历这么多的灾难啊
乐观点 乐观点
窗户窗户窗户
噢 不
该死的 你是在开玩笑吧 你差点害死…
我只说 这风景可真美啊
他看起来像只鸭子 走路也像只鸭子 而且闻起来像玉米热狗…
好吧 到底哪只是维克多？
什么？你竟然认不出你的父亲？
- 我们走 - 这些兄弟怎么办？
不能把他妈留在这里等着被吃掉
你们只是初次见面
相见就是缘分 我们不能扔下他们
拜托 先把他妈救了吧
我的身上简直脏透了
好像被猫舔过一样
哦 拜托 没那么糟糕吧
尽管我没有… 啊 真是猫
- 我的脸 我的脸 - 盖上
- 真棒 - 谢谢
着陆了
维克茜 过来帮忙把门关上
- 谢谢了 大鸟 - 再见
这可真疯狂
再见 大鸟 我很开心
吔
- 击掌 - 击掌
海库斯 海库斯 海库斯
有个女孩一起玩 这感觉还真好
你在干什么呢？
我只是在拥抱你
难道你没被拥抱过吗？
维克茜
- 海库斯抱抱 海库斯抱抱 - 海库斯
海库斯 海库斯
海库斯
我觉得应该让它留在这里快一点
谢谢
也许 他们现在正在对蓝妹妹做着什么可怕的事情
是啊 蓝妹妹很需要我们 也许她现在非常害怕
- 我们是一家人 - 什么？
她在干什么？
我认为是拥抱
爸爸？
海库斯喜欢拥抱
海库斯
蓝妹妹 过来 我给你看样东西
看看我们 告诉我们 我们不是一家人吗？
蓝妹妹
这边
很遗憾蓝爸爸没有来找你
也许你的家就在这里我们在一起
是啊
也许是吧
她为什么跟他们那么好呢？
她这是认同了她的绑架者 典型的斯特哥尔摩综合症
不 她认为我们不在乎她了 而他们在乎
她被迷迷惑了
笨笨 厌厌 爬上去帮助我把门打开
- 我的女儿在里面 - 好的 爸爸
- 我到把手上 - 好的 厌厌 你跳 我来拉
- 加油 我们能做到 - 孩子们
- 格格巫 - 不要松手
啊 爸爸回来啦
本性善良的好爸爸给你带了一件礼物
厌厌 下来 别让他看见
- 我们现在应该怎么解救她？- 安静
亲爱的 我认为我们之间一定有误会
这是怎么回事？
我祝福你拥有一个非常非常快乐的生日？
一切就似乎发生在昨天
你还仅仅是我手中一小团粘土个其他腐败的配料
你居然能记得我的生日？
当然记得呀 我们是一家人了
- 什么？- 可是我们才是她的家人
- 她是不是认为我们抛弃她了？- 家人是不会忘记这种事情的
说到这个这个话题你按蓝色的小继父好像还没回来是吧？
继父？
我真的感到才l每限遗憾 亲爱的 你的心肯定很疼
我还记得我父亲把我扔到井里第一次的时候
他脸上那失望的表情啊
当他看见我很艰难的从井里爬出来的时候
不说了 生日快乐 亲爱的
- 生日快乐 蓝妹妹 - 生日快乐 蓝妹妹
- 我要打开 我要打开 - 哦 不不不
真难看
"鞠躬鞠躬 敬个礼"
模仿的真像 真的
再嘲笑我就把你变成一只斗鸡眼的娃娃鱼
嗯 亲爱的
拿起来看看
这是专门给你定制的一柄小小的魔杖
拿着吧 这是你的生日礼物
不
千万不要
你喜欢它吗？
我真傻 忘记激活它了
嗯 好了
是的 我们走
这就对了嘛随便玩 用不着害怕
- 是龙魔杖 - 天哪
随便玩 今天是你的生日
你怎么知道我不会用这个对付你？
好吧…
因为 蓝妹妹 我是你爸爸
想想你的感觉 你就会知道这是真的
- 她一定会杀了他 - 攻击他 蓝妹妹
蓝妹妹
给我唱首歌
快唱
这很好 不是吗 爸爸？
不 她会变得和他们一员
这是我一直想做的事
哦 不能失去它
- 吔 干得好 蓝妹妹 - 这是你第一次动手
看看呐 看看呐
哦 你可真是一个爸爸的好女孩
- 蓝妹妹 - 不 爸爸 厌厌抓住他
- 不 爸爸 他会看见你的 - 快帮我把爸爸弄下来
- 笨笨 帮帮忙 帮我把他弄下来 - 爸爸 不
吔
不
啊 飞吧 兄弟们 终于自由啦 终于自由啦
- 你以为你是马丁·路德飞？- 随便吧
尽管取笑我吧孩子 为了自由而奋斗我自豪我幸福我快乐
不
那是哥哥 什么？
简直是侮辱蓝精灵 维克多马上就到
打开精灵伞
飞翔的维克多成功啦
成功啦
好了 别害怕
维克多的皮肤这么白啊
别害怕
我没有长大
真是太好啦
- 他是光着的 是吧？- 大家都还好吧？
没事吧？救命 救命 来人啊 救救我
我看见一个好恐怖的东西在下面
但愿以后不要天天做噩梦
蓝妹妹呢？
- 她… - 蓝妹妹呢？
已经太迟了
干得漂亮
尽情玩吧 孩子们 一定要记住 对人家要友好
滚远点 你这个笨手笨脚的傻瓜
- 蓝精灵来过？- 什么？
蓝精灵们来过这里 那你怎么不说呀？
我说了
她肯定还不知道
我们必须要带她离开这里 然后得到配方
蓝妹妹 亲爱的 准备去庆祝生日吧
- 吔 - 来吧 很有意思
我们差点就把蓝妹妹救回来了
我知道
可他在关键时刻让我分心了 格蕾丝
如果不是他 我不会错过电梯的
好了 别那么大声 帕特里克 试着深呼吸
希望他快点走
- 他是你爸爸 - 不 他根本不是我爸爸
他说的没错 我不是他爸爸
他亲身爸爸离开他组建了新的家庭
他一直解不开这个心结
- 你在说什么？- 我理解你的感受
但我 不希望你一直这样下去
嘿 我可没求着你让你闯入我的生活 明白？
也没请你和我妈妈结婚 更没有请你带走宙斯
宙斯？那只鸽子？
是鹦鹉
是我的鹦鹉
因为你过敏就把它送人了
不是我对鹦鹉过敏
是 就是你
不是我
是你
什么？
当时你每天都喘息 咳嗽 很严重
你母亲和我都知道鹦鹉
离开你会伤心欲绝的 因为你
你的爸爸的事已经伤害了你
所以才骗了你
你在编故事 我怎么可能… 我对鸟类从来就不过敏
来 试试
闻闻这羽毛
- 我才不闻呢… - 快点闻闻
鼻子很痒是吧？
听我说帕特里克
我是真心爱你母亲的
我尽心的照顾她 我努力的让她开心
我也曾经想爱亲儿子一样的爱你
其实我可以不那么做
可你那么一点的孩子 却没了父亲 眼里全是绝望心里满是伤痕
所以我努力的去疼你
我做到了
可是你并不想要 那好吧
我对你的忠告就是
成熟点？
不要因为自己的痛苦去责怪别人
不论你做什么
千万别让你那漂亮的儿子觉得爱是有条件的
因为爱是无条件的
再见 格蕾丝
再见 布鲁
威斯特爷爷再见
再见
再见 帕特里克·温斯洛
快看 大轮子
哦 过来 跟我来 亲爱的
这就是大家都叫它光之城的原因
这里好多人哦
是啊 其实
我更喜欢叫他们崇拜者
"崇拜者"
阿拉塔
跪下
海库斯
- 怎么样？- 走吧
别担心 他们都喜欢这样 他是大明星
好吧
真好 是我
- 这是我的孩子们 - 嗨
- 这是谁呀？- 这是我弟弟
嘿 海库斯
你看呐 多神奇的小东西
嗨
今天是我生日
谢谢
- 我有速通卡 - 是的 速通卡
哦 格格巫先生
啊 谢谢你帮我们预热了座位 再见
拜拜
过来 孩子们 这边走
格格巫先生 格格巫先生
快来啊
- 爸爸 - 等会儿
吃饭时间到了
- 等一会 - 但是
我们到了
- 好戏刚刚才开始 对吗？- 吔
阿拉塔 转起来
是不是感觉很有趣啊 亲爱的
想想看
设想一下秘方和我不可思议的魔法
天底下还有什么事我们做不到的呢？
是的
想象我们将拥有的乐趣吧 蓝妹妹
好吧
我们为什么不能转的快点呢？
- 注意 - 吔
这样更好玩吧？
一点都不好玩
这真是太好玩了 蓝妹妹 太棒了
来了
当心下面啊 摩天轮来了哦
抱歉
是我让她失望了
抱歉 我只是 想一个人静一静
不不不 没什么的
我也是在反思我自己呢
温斯洛先生 这对我很难
不过你能给我一些建议吗？
因为 你也是个父亲
是关于蓝妹妹的
我不知道该怎么做
我把她变蓝了
教给她爱 和善良
但实际上是格格巫制造了她
只要她愿意 她随时可以是个蓝精灵
但是 如果她不愿意呢
如果她选择了格格巫
我们不能失去她
也许已经失去她了
也许我做的还不够
你开玩笑吧？
格格巫只是制造了她
但是你 你给了她新的生命
你关心她爱她像对自己的孩子一样
没人要求你 但你这样做了
因为你知道她想要这些
这是…
这是一种非常特殊的爱
她那么聪明她一定会想明白的
嗯 说的对
是我们的信任让她变成了蓝精灵
而改变 又让我们产生了担忧
谢谢你 温斯洛先生
你的话让我心里豁然开朗
我也是
这有几个泡泡
这个算吗？
哦 真是臭死人了 你都吃了些什么呀？
不至于吧？每次我放屁的时候都会有人笑的
- 该出发了 孩子们 - 去哪儿
去带蓝妹妹回家
但是您看到了 爸爸
她现在已经改变了
- 变成木马人了？- 不
- 加入社会党了？- 不
啊 是空中飞人
变成捣蛋鬼了 别打岔
不管我们看到了什么
我们永远都不能放弃我们的家人
对 爸爸说的对
你是谁？你和厌厌到底什么关系？
嘿 我的保持乐观 忘了吗？
好吧 孩子们 我们去找蓝妹妹吧
温斯洛先生 你也一起去吗？
蓝精灵的屁股是蓝色的？
你自己看嘛
厌厌
- 注意点影响 - 还有人看吗？
好了没有？快出来吧
- 我们要准备开工啦 - 嘿
都打起精神来 出发了
对 伙伴们 开始行动吧
维克多？你好
好的 温斯洛先生 我们分头行动吧
好的 我去找到供电室 切掉电源
我们去找蓝妹妹
我们会英俊潇洒的做好事情的
哦 拜托
团队形象 明白吗？
好吧 里面见 好运
- 走吧 伙伴们 - 我们去虎口拔牙
我们来这里做什么 爸爸？
来给你这个有点认生的姐姐庆祝生日啊
真的？
没有蛋糕怎么算是完整的生日呢？
一个蛋糕
这是你最喜欢的 我的蓝色的小可爱
蛋糕
来吧来吧 许个愿 亲爱的
无论什么 只要你的小脑袋能想的到的 都会变成现实
无论什么？
当然了
前提是我力所能及
因为最近我的精灵精华使用的有点超预算了
要不然我也不会跟你要配方 是吧？
哦 她在那
那是她的生日蛋糕吗？
我们也给她准备了一个生日蛋糕
只不过 她根本就没有看见
他们看起来像是幸福的一家人
她是不会给他配方的
对吧 爸爸？如果她给了那就意昧着整个精灵族的灭亡
等等 包括最帅的那个吗？
- 当然 - 福福 你跟我来
笨笨和厌厌去跟温斯洛先生会合
维克多 你来干嘛？
格蕾丝说
你可能需要帮助
哦 不不 维克多 等等
其实格蕾丝说的对
我的确需要帮助
我认为你应该打开供电井盖
除非 你想检查电话线
蓝妹妹 配方呢？
抓紧一切时间考虑考虑
亲爱的 只是时间实在不多了
我们就都可以变蓝了 在一起
海库斯要变蓝 海库斯要变蓝
看到了吗 他想变蓝
就像他们的姐姐一样
那么 我们就真的是一家人了
这个配方
是一份珍贵的礼物也是对我的信任
对不起
我不能…
把它给你
什么意思？你不能？
我给了你一切
善良 礼物
一个没有毒的蛋糕 你就这样对待我么
现在我受够了 年轻的小姐
你必须马上把配方交出来
- 马上交出来 - 不
必须
- 爸爸？- 什么 什么 什么？
海库斯头晕
他们这是怎么了？
头晕
别告诉我你真的很在乎这些悲哀的东西
瞧瞧你多伤心呐
真是上天赐给我一个绝妙的机会
好像这条才是电线
快点快点 我们要救出蓝妹妹
好了 快点行动吧
这边 福福 穿过这跟管道
我一定要救出她 这下是我大显身手的时刻
真抱歉 亲爱的 我想你应该知道
没有精华他们会死的
- 爸爸 - 不
求你了
不 维克茜
好晕啊
- 海库斯 - 蓝妹妹
快把精华给他们 从我这取吧
从我这儿取
求你了
问题是如果你不把精灵配方给我
我就管不了他们啦
维克茜
你是说 你先让他们死
对 我还可以制造新的
再说了 让他们死的那个人又不是我
而是你
好的 好的
我答应你 快点喂他们
那你先给我配方
快救他们 快救他们
快点 得马上赶到那里
- 是死路 - 被锁上了
配方 啦啦啦…
用思想的火花
加上一滴蜂王浆
害羞草花粉
蓝妹妹
- 蓝妹妹 - 真是个好姑娘
我听不见说话 但能看到他们
等等 我知道了
爸爸快看
- 一滴精华液 - 我知道
再加一滴… - 难道她把配方给他了？
- 不 - 蓝妹妹
快帮我把它打开
还有 你必须说出一种爱的本质
- 当然能 - 给
这就是蓝爸爸用的配方
快点救他们
先检验一下配方是否有效 ？
快点
- 快 - 就这了
快 快
使劲 帕特里克 加把劲
- 开呀 - 嘿 这下面有个路口
- 快来 保持乐观 - 好的 让他们灭火
一种爱的本质
希望这能有效
海库斯
- 蓝妹妹 谢谢你 - 维克茜
我的精灵 成功啦
- 海库斯 - 海库斯变蓝了
海库斯
海库斯变蓝了
我们变蓝了 我们是精灵了
成功了 全世界都是我的了
- 我可以制造自己的精灵啦 - 不
哦 蓝妹妹 背叛了我们
终于 终于
你们成为真正的蓝精灵啦
我是蓝的
现在都给我进机器里面去
爸爸 不要
- 别把我关起来 别把我关起来 - 好的 好的
- 别把我关起来 - 进去吧
- 每个人都有自己的房间 - 请
- 哎 福福 我失去了她 - 爸爸 等等
我应该能够到门闩
好主意 福福
快点快点
爸爸 求你了
不要乱跑啊
你脸都哭花了
海库斯哭了
海库斯也哭了
为了救我和海库斯 你失去了一切
没办法
我在乎你们
我们是一家人
我不喜欢哭泣
我喜欢蓝色
多么肉麻的一幕啊
如果这不是我人生中最开心的时刻
我会被你们恶心的吐出胆汁来
- 门控制杆 大的那个 - 踩着我的肩膀
小伙子 快点
该往那边掰？
往负极 就是断电
负极 哦 不 我是积极乐观的
哪里
这仅仅是一个巫师的一小部分
但对我来说 却是… 什么？
我是正极
好沉的浆果馅饼
厌厌
哦 对了 我说过 让你来按下按钮
骗你的 这是我的一大步
我被电到了
保持乐观可真不容易啊
啊 真是气死我了
快点 福福
看看自恋狂是怎么带你们脱险的
- 开了 - 干的漂亮
- 当然 - 快走
- 什么？- 走
快点 阿兹猫
幸亏我有宇宙能量作为备用电源
关键时刻我的运气总那么好？
- 这边 - 瞧瞧我 多帅气的身手
简直就是蓝精灵特战队员
嘘
哦 你说的对 特战队应该悄悄的行动
遵命
- 你看 她在那 - 蓝妹妹
圣诞老人
爸爸？你…你来救我了
哦 我当然会来救你的 你是我的女儿
这有什么好怀疑的呢？
- 锁上了 - 你们钻进去
- 我们去找别的路 - 好吧
好的 里面会合 温斯洛先生 快点
这里
好了 挂上去
哦 爸爸
哦 亲爱的
爸爸 我把配方给了格格巫
但是她救了我们
海库斯还活着 海库斯还活着
哦 爸爸 我让您失望了
我 背叛了蓝精灵
我真的很抱歉
哦 蓝妹妹 只有生命才是最值得我们保护的
我为你感到骄傲
你…真的？
真的吗？不打屁股 连手板也不打一下
难道就这样原谅她了吗？
当然了 因为爱会让我们变得很强大
失去爱也就失去了所有的希望
真的好感动 我又要哭了
嗨 小蓝妹妹
哦 你好啊
嗨
我们没有时间了
我们得赶快抢回配方 离开这个鬼地方
等等 他们怎么办？
他们怎么办？他们绑架了你
他们是格格巫的人
我也一样 但是 爸爸从来没放弃我
所以 我也不能丢下他们不管
除非你认为自己不是真正的蓝精灵
- 带他们出去 快点 - 好的 爸爸
海库斯自由了
又来了四个？
你好 猫咪
欢迎参加聚会 爸爸
哦 瞧瞧这些小宝贝
我爱你们做的事 我爱死你们了
真的太可爱了 尤其你们这蓝色的样子
我们快变成肉酱了
快住手 格格巫
够你用的啦
是的是的 但你看 蓝爸爸 我还想更多的呢
海库斯好疼啊 我现在能让它发挥作用了
我叫它 拉旺达
你以为它是个魔杖
所以我叫它拉旺达 多有意思啊
如果你不正难受着 肯定也会为我高兴的
相信我 可是我有这么多能量 到底用来干什么呢？
哦 我想到了
用这些能量 我可以统治全世界
不
哦 还有蓝爸爸
我忘告诉你我的第一个正式行动
我要创造一个入口
直接从那到我这儿到达蓝精灵村
这样就可以让所有的蓝精灵来这里陪你啦
是永远
我可不这么想 格格巫
就这样
- 快来 让我来 - 快啊
他就要拿到魔杖了
- 快点把它砸开 - 我这么帅可不能死啊
以精灵之爱的名义
别光站在那儿吼我 快打碎它
开啦
阿拉塔…
我肚子好疼口阿
我们又被扔出来啦
当心 笨笨
- 每一次 - 对不起
真的？
击掌
都没事吧？
所有的精灵 一个都不少
- 帕特里克 - 爸爸
- 嘿 - 嘿 格蕾丝
嘿
我们成功了
嗨 格蕾丝
蓝妹妹
哦 我好想你哦
我好担心你啊
格蕾丝 这是维克茜 我的妹妹
那也就是我的妹妹了
你没事吧？
幸福的感觉就是这样的吗？
你好 漂亮的小姐 我也很漂亮
他叫海库斯 我的弟弟
海库斯
海库斯 这是格蕾丝和帕特里克
- 嗨 - 这是… 你的孩子？
他叫布鲁
你好幸福啊 格蕾丝
他可真漂亮
他是谁他是谁？
他是维克多 他是…
他是…
他是我的爸爸
是布鲁的很了不起的爷爷
爸爸和维克多爷爷
行了 我感觉到了
我为你自豪 帕特里克·温斯洛
再加上道尔
再加上蓝精灵
对 伙计们 蓝精灵全返
- 维克茜 - 做的好 做的好
- 保持乐观？- 嘿 离我远点
我从来不玩这个
我是厌厌 我的天性就是愤怒和讨厌
哇 感觉真好
我回来啦
我也回来啦
好极了
我想你们应该都知道拉旺达
- 太不幸了 - …一个非常有意思的词
- 蓝妹妹 - 问好吧 向我伟大的朋友问好吧
我不这么认为 格格巫
吔
不 拉旺达 哦 不
告诉我哪能关掉我的魔杖？
不不不 拉旺达
不…
不 拉旺达 不是这样的
真让我受伤啦
- 太棒了蓝妹妹 太棒了 - 好样的 蓝妹妹
真是太奇妙了
现在可以暂时摆脱格格巫了
我们回家吧 一起回家
- 好的 - 回家
我们还有一个很小的问题
我只剩下五颗水晶了
我要说 一个蓝精灵都不能少
哇 蓝妹妹
你把魔杖用的出神入化啊
这是我天生的能力
曾经非常困扰我
但是 就像一位伟大的人告诉我的
你来自哪里并不重要
重要的是你想要做什么样的人
这才是我的女儿
您是我们的爸爸
谢谢您给了我们一个新的住所
一个新的家庭
您真的是一个好爸爸
你也会是个好精灵
我会想你们的
可以用他们命名热狗
哦 这主意不错 可以用蓝玉米来做
蓝精灵热狗 吔
对
一路顺风 伙伴们
精灵们要回家了
再次感谢你 温斯洛先生
还有多利特小姐
小道尔
啊 维克多爷爷
- 再见了 温斯洛一家 - 再见 爸爸
- 再见 - 再见 - 再见
- 好了 出发吧 孩子们 - 再见 温斯洛一家
我等不及想见家里的伙伴们了
再见 蓝精灵
- 哎 你又压着我了 - 抱歉
爸爸 您找到蓝妹妹了
欢迎回家 蓝妹妹
- 快看这里 - 吔 我们回来了
- 嗨 伙计们 - 真是太好了
我们的大家庭又添新成员
伙伴们 这位就是维克茜
- 哦 - 她真是个小美人
嗨
- 嗨… - 嗨 我是蓝蓝
嗨 我是蓝蓝 你喜欢吃蛋糕吗？
- 哎呀 - 怎么呢？
我差点被吓尿裤子
海库斯
海库斯 他们是你的新兄弟
啊 有新兄弟啦
抱一抱
听我说一句
从法律上来讲
根据蓝精灵规章第六条 宗系的合法性 像这种生物…
嘿 踢他一脚
- 这种生物不能… - 吃海库斯一脚
- 吔 - 这小子有个性
他跟我们一样
所以在耐心的等待之后 主题再一次浮现
我们的故事大王荣耀回归 发挥主导作用
他特别提醒大家 我们上次见面的时候
整个村庄正忙成一团 他们精心的准备着
嗨 这些装饰是怎么回事？
生日快乐 蓝妹妹
能安静点吗？故事马上就要结束了
- 从此… - 嗨 开始狂欢吧
但是音乐却压过了叙述的声音
献给我新的大家庭
啊 不 不不 救救我 拉旺达
救命救命啊 救我啊 拉旺达
你别想溜？过来陪我
你怎么能这么说我？我什么都没做错
巴黎已经是过去式了 朋友
我们回来了 你最好意识到这点
你想要客房服务吗 为啥不朝窗外喊叫？
阿兹猫先生 难道你只有在用爪子的时候才秀出来吗？
阿兹猫 阿兹猫 阿兹猫
停下来 别抓脸 不要抓我的脸
~ 我的宝贝 不要害羞
~ 我看到你眼中的火花闪烁
~ 我的心跳的很快 因为有我想要的一切
~ 所以宝贝 和我一起做 哦啦啦
~ 牵我的手 我们每个晚上都可以一起出去
~ 让我天旋地转 目眩神迷 我喜欢这样
~ 这种感觉太棒了 我还想要更多
~ 所以宝贝 和我一起做 哦啦啦
~ 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦 啦
~ 你不要穿不是为你量身定制的衣服
~ 如果我们在地上跳舞
~ 手指放在我的头发里 什么都不想
~ 今晚
~ 只要自由
~ 没有人能像我们这样疯狂
~ 没嗨到爆 我们一秒都不会停下来
~ 来吧 我喇叭的音乐开到最大
~ 然后打破束缚 秀出你自己
~ 哦 宝贝 不要害羞
~ 我看到你眼里闪闪发光的火花
~ 我的心跳的很快 因为有我想要的一切
~ 所以宝贝 和我一起做 哦啦啦